Welcome to this video course on
Langraph, the powerful Python library
for building advanced conversational AI
workflows. In this course, Vbeca will
teach you how to design, implement, and
manage complex dialogue systems using a
graph-based approach. By the end, you'll
be equipped to build robust, scalable,
conversational applications that
leverage the full potential of large
language models. Hey guys, my name is
Vava and I'm a robotics and AI student.
In this course, we're going to be
learning all about the fundamentals of
Langraph. Now, I assume you've heard of
Langraph before, hence why you clicked
on this course. But I'm also going to
assume you have never coded in Langraph
before. Now, because of this assumption,
I have explained every single thing in
as much detail as I possibly can. Now,
also this might mean that I might be
going slow at times. So if you want you
can always speed me up. Now what are we
going to be learning in this course?
Well to start we're going to be building
a lot of graphs, a lot of AI agents.
We're going to be learning a lot about
the theory and I've also provided
exercises throughout the course in which
all of the answers will be provided on
the
GitHub. With that being said, if you're
ready to start on this journey with me,
let's go to our first section
then. All right people. So welcome to
the first section of this course. Now in
this section we'll be covering something
called as type annotations. Now
admittedly this is going to be a
completely theoretical section but it
will be short and brief. I promise. The
reason I've kept this specific section
in the course is because when we do
eventually go on to code uh our AI
agents, our graphs and langraph, these
will start popping up everywhere. And I
don't really want you to look start
coding without ever having seen these
before or really not knowing what these
actually are. So that's why I've kept it
here. But I promise this will be short
and brief. Cool. Okay. Let's begin with
dictionaries. Now dictionaries are a
data structure. Yes, but there's a
reason I've kept it here. So let's see
how a dictionary is described in Python.
You should already know this. So in this
case, I've described a very simple
dictionary called uh movie. and it has
two keys, the name and the year. And it
has two values, Avengers Endgame and
2019. Now, dictionaries are awesome,
don't get me wrong. They're they allow
for efficient data retrieval based on
their unique keys. They're flexible and
easy to implement, but there's a
potential problem with them. See, it's a
challenge to ensure that the data is a
particular structure. And this could be
a huge problem in larger projects. So to
put things in simple words, it doesn't
really check if the data is the correct
type data type or structure and that
could be the source of a lot of logical
errors in your project. And if your
project is really really large, then
this could be quite a headache to
identify, right? Cuz it's quite a small
detail. So what is the solution for
this? Well, it's something called a type
dictionary. Now, here is an example on
how you create a type dictionary in
Python. And I just want to uh emphasize
that this type annotation is used
extensively in langraph. This will be
used to define states. Now don't worry
you we haven't covered states yet. We
will cover that in the next section. But
just be mindful that this is quite
important. So a type dictionary is quite
easy to implement. You implement it as a
class. In this case, I've implemented
the same um example I uh uh showed you
in the previous section where I
described the movie is the same exact
keys and values. So, it still has the
name and the year. But notice in this
class, I have defined the actual uh data
type of what that key should be. So, for
example, the name is a string and the
year is an integer, right? And to
initialize a dictionary uh I have done
the exact same thing. to have engineet
game in 2019. So now there are two main
uh benefits of using a type dictionary
it's type safety because we've
explicitly defined what should be in
this data structure and so this will
really reduce the runtime errors and
obviously the readability is enhanced as
well and this will make debugging easier
if something goes wrong within this type
dictionary. Cool. So we've covered type
dictionary now. Now we move on to
another type of annotation which is
union. Now you might have seen these
future these later uh types annotations
before if you coded in Python but again
I'm just giving you a highle overview
what these are. So union take a look at
this example. So I've created a very
simple function which takes in a value
and it squares it. Now in this case the
uh input x could be either an integer or
float and union basically says that
whatever value you have can be these
data types only. So in this case x can
only be integer or float. So if I pass
in five or 1.23 4 this would be
completely fine. It would square the
number and everything. But if I passed
in a string like I am a string it would
completely fail. Now admittedly yes this
function is quite easy. If I passed in
I'm a string, it would have failed
anyway. But in more complicated
applications, hopefully you can see how
this actually is useful. In fact, the
makers of Lang Chain and Langraph used
Union quite extensively throughout u
making the actual library. So again,
it's flexible and it's easy to code and
it allows for type safety. So because it
can provide hints to uh help catch
incorrect usage. Now something similar
to union is another type annotation
which is optional. Now optional is quite
similar and in this case I've described
another function nice message. So you
pass in a name. If you pass in a name it
will say hi there name. So for example
let the name be Bob. If I pass in Bob to
this uh function it would say hi there
Bob. But what if I don't pass in
anything? Now if I don't pass anything
optional because I've used optional says
that the name parameter could either be
a string or a none value. Now if I pass
in nothing it will go in this if
statement and say hey random person. But
this is also important to emphasize that
it cannot be anything else. It can't be
an integer or or a boolean or a float or
anything like that. It has to be either
a string or a none value because that's
what I've defined here. Cool. Now comes
another type annotation called any. And
any is really the easiest one to
understand. It literally means this
value could be anything. It could be any
data structure. So in this case I've
created a simple um function called
print value where it takes in something
and it prints that. And for example I
passed in this string and it prints it
and anything and everything is allowed.
Cool. one last type annotation I promise
and it's the lambda function. So lambda
functions are quite useful. For example,
in this I'll give you two examples now.
So the first example is this really
simple uh example. Now we've already I
already created a square function
before, right? Where it takes in a
value, it takes in a number and it
squares it. So for example, if I passed
in square 10, it would give me 100.
Quite an easy example. Now let me give
you a second
example. this. So if you've come from a
leaf code background, then you've
probably seen you've either used lambda
before and you've definitely used math
before cuz it's quite efficient. So for
example, if I pass in 1 2 3 4, what this
piece of code is saying is that it
squares each number in nums. So this map
function maps each value uh and performs
this function to it. So x * x. So 1 4 9
16 and then converts that back into a
list. Now lambda functions really are
just a shortcut to writing small
functions and they make everything quite
efficient. Now obviously this could have
been done in one line as well but for
example this a beginner programmer could
have might have used a for loop but a
more advanced programmer could have used
this and this is obviously much more
efficient. Right? So hopefully you can
start to see what how powerful these
type annotations are and these will be
coming up. So again, no need to memorize
this. Just need to have a highle
overview what they are. Okay, cool. So
now I'll see you in the next section.
See you
there. All right, perfect. So let's
continue on. In this section, we will
look at the different elements in
Langraph. So let's begin with our first
element, one of the most fundamental
elements in all of Langraph, the state.
So what is a state? Well, it's a shared
data structure that holds the current
information or context of the entire
application. In simpler terms, it is
like the application's memory where it
keeps track of the variables, the data
that nodes can access and modify as they
execute. Now, don't worry if you don't
understand what a node is yet. That is
what we will be talking in the next
slide about. But as a good analogy,
think of the whiteboard in a meeting
room analogy.
Now imagine you're in a meeting room and
there are different participants as well
and every time you come up with
something new or you want to record some
new uh information or update some
information you write it on the
whiteboard. In this case the whiteboard
acts as your state and the participants
act as a
node. So the state shows us the updated
content/in information of your entire
application. Hopefully that made a bit
of sense.
So let's move on to the node another
fundamental element in lang graph. So
these are just individual functions or
operations that perform specific tasks
within the graph. So each of these node
receives an input which is often just
the current state of your application.
It processes it and then produces an
output or an updated
state. So here's a good analogy of this.
The assembly line station analogy. Now
look at this image. Each of these
station does one specific job. It could
be attaching a part. It could be
painting it. It could be inspecting the
quality and so on and so on. The point
is each of these stations represent a
node because they do one specific
task. So how do you actually connect
these different nodes together? Well,
before we go into that, I think it's
important we understand the most
important element of them all, the
graph. It is so important that it's even
in the name Langraph. So, the graph is
just the overarching structure and it
maps out how different tasks aka nodes
are connected and executed. So it
visually represents the workflow showing
the sequence and the conditional parts
between various
operations. Now a graph is quite
self-explanatory but you can think of it
as a road map. On a road map you can see
it display the different routes
connecting cities with the different
intersections offering choices on which
path to take next.
Now, here's a great image of what a
graph is, and these are the individual
nodes, but you'll see they're connected
somehow. So, how are these connected?
That brings us to the next element,
edges. So, edges are just the connection
between nodes and these determine the
flow of
execution. So, they tell us or tell the
application which node should be
executed next after the current one
completes its task. A really good
analogy of this is imagining a train
track. So this is the train track and
think of it as an edge and think of it
as connecting two stations one here and
one here which represent nodes together
in a specific
direction. Now the train which will go
on the train track that acts as your
state. So the state gets updated from
one station to another.
But there is another type of an edge and
it's called a conditional
edge. So this is still not very
complicated. It's quite simple to
understand. These are just specialized
connections that decide the next node to
be executed based on the specific
condition or logic applied to the
current state. Now a really good analogy
for this is the traffic light analogy.
So green could mean to go one way, red
could mean to stop. yellow could mean to
slow down. The point I'm trying to make
here is that the condition, in this case
the light color, it decides the next
step. If you want to think even more
simply, you could think about an if else
statement. So that being said, we move
on to the next element, the start point.
So the start point or the node, the
start node is a virtual entry point in
langraph and this marks where the
workflow begins. Now it's important to
note that it doesn't perform any
operations itself but it serves as the
designated starting position for the
graph's
execution. Now in terms of analogy it is
quite simple to understand but if you
really want think of it as the starting
line of
race. Now if you have a start point well
you need an end point as well and that's
where the end element comes in. So the
end nodes just signifies the conclusion
of the workflow in Langraph. So when the
application reaches this node, the
graph's execution completely stops and
it indicates that all intended processes
have been
completed. And again, a good analogy for
this is just the finish line in a
race. So nothing too hard yet. But now
let's look at
tools. So tools are specialized
functions or utilities that nodes can
utilize to perform specific tasks. For
example, it could be fetching data from
an
API. They basically enhance the
capabilities of these nodes by providing
additional
functionalities. Now, one common
question could be, well, what's the
difference between a tool and a node?
The node is just the part of the graph
structure. Whereas the tools, these guys
are functionalities used within the
nodes. Now, a really good analogy for
this is just tools in a toolbox. So
imagine a hammer for the nails, a
screwdriver for the screws, etc. The
point is each tool has a distinct
purpose. Again, don't worry. You will
understand the differentiation between
tools and nodes in a lot more detail
later when we code this, but this is
just for a general
overview. Now, another question you
could be asking is, is there a middleman
between a tool and a node? Short answer
is yes. That's where tool node comes in.
So a tool node is just a special kind of
a node whose main job is to run a
tool. So for example, a tool node could
be a node where its only job is to use a
tool and that tool's job is to fetch
some data from an
API. So it connects the tools output
back into the state so other nodes can
use that information.
So think about this analogy going back
to the assembly line. In this case,
imagine the operator as the tool node
and it controls the machine which is the
tool and then sends all of these results
back into this assembly
line. Now if we progress further, let's
look at the state graph. So this is
quite an important element as well. This
will be one of the first elements you
actually interact with and its main
purpose is to build and compile the
graph structure. So it's quite
important. It manages the nodes, the
edges, the overall state and it makes
sure that the workflow operates in a
unified way and all of the data flows
correctly between components. So again
it's quite an important element. You can
think about it as a blueprint of a
building. So just as a blueprint
outlines the design and the connections
within a building, the state graph does
exactly that, but it just defines the
structure and the flow of your workflow
or
application. Now here's where the
runnable comes in. Now some of you will
be coming from a lang chain background
and runnable is quite common there and
it's quite similar in langraph as well.
A runnable in langraph is just the
standardized executable component that
performs a specific task within an AI
workflow. It basically acts as a
fundamental building block allowing for
us to create these modular
systems. Now a question you could have
right now is well what's the difference
between a runnable and a node?
Short answer is a runnable can represent
various operations whereas a node in
lang lang graph typically receives a
state performs an action on them and
then updates the state. Now don't worry
if you didn't 100% get that when we go
into the coding section you will get it
a lot better. But a good analogy is a
Lego brick. So just as how Lego bricks
can be snapped together to build these
complicated structures, runnables can be
combined to create sophisticated AI
workflows. So now let's move on to the
different types of
messages. Now again, if you come from a
lang chain background, you'll be quite
familiar with these. If you haven't,
don't worry. We will look at the five
most common message types in Langraph.
So to start off, there's the human
message which represents the input from
a user. The AI message which represents
responses generated by AI models. The
system message which is used to provide
instructions or context to the
model. Tool message which is similar to
the function message but specific to
tool usage. And the function message
represents the tool of a function call.
If you've used an API like a large
language model API before, such as
OpenAI's API, a lot of these will be
quite familiar, especially the system
message, the AI message, and the human
message. And that concludes this
section. So, I will see you in the next
section. Awesome. So, now this is quite
exciting. We're actually about to start
coding in Langra for the very first
time. Now that we've covered all the
theory, admittedly the boring section,
we're now actually going to code up some
graphs. And we're about to code up our
very first graph in this sub section.
But um for this overall section, I have
a slight confession to make, which is
we're not going to be building any AI
agents in this
section. Why? because I thought that one
we haven't really even seen uh how to
actually code in Langraph and combining
all of these LLMs APIs and tools and all
of that stuff which comes with it
combining them together would be quite
messy and it could be quite confusing at
times especially the fact that we have
never coded in Langraph before again
like I said at the beginning of the
course this course is supposed to be
beginner friendly detailed and
comprehensive and we're going to go in
steps like little by little so hopefully
understand but don't worry we will be
coding AI agents soon we're just going
to be building a couple of graphs right
now uh understand lang graph better the
syntax better and how to actually code
up graphs and get confident with it and
then we will actually build AI agents
okay cool so what is the graph which
we're going to be building together in
this section I call it the uh hello
world graph mainly because it's the most
basic form of graph we can actually code
in lang graph so the objectives are
these
So we're going to be understanding and
defining the agent state structure and
don't worry you'll understand what that
is in a few minutes and we're going to
be creating simple node functions nodes
like we discussed in the previous
section uh and we're going to be
processing them and updating the state.
We're going to be building the first
ever basic langraph structure and we
will understand how to compile it,
invoke it, process it, everything. And
really the main goal of this section is
to really understand how data flows
through a single node in langraph. Now
just to give you a bit of a heads up as
to what we'll actually be covering uh
what we're going to be building I should
say is this graph. Again like I said
this is the most basic form of graph you
can build in langraph. It has a start
point and an end point and this node
sandwiched in between them. All right
cool. So hopefully you've understood
what the objectives are. It's quite
basic and yeah, I'll see you at the
code. Okay, cool. Now let's actually
code this very first graph. So I've
imported three main things here. The
dict, the type dict and the state graph.
The dict and type dict is obviously
dictionary and type dictionary but um
and state graph. These three are
elements which we covered in the
previous section. So I would highly
recommend you going back there if these
are completely unfamiliar. But again you
don't need to memorize what these are.
Okay. But just to refresh your memory
I've written in the comment here what
the state graph is. So think of the
state graph as a framework that helps
you design and manage the flow of the
tasks in your application. Um again that
might sound a bit complicated but it's
not. Once we actually start coding you
will it'll make more sense. So now the
first thing we're going to do after
importing everything is create the state
of our agent and let's call it agent
state. And just to refresh your memory
again what the state is. Think of the
state as a shared data structure. And
this keeps track of the your all of the
information as the application runs. All
right cool. So now let's build the agent
state. And the way we do this in
Langraph is through a class. So let's
build class agent state and in this in
these parenthesis we will try to the the
state needs to be in the form of a typed
dictionary. So that's why we specify
type dictionary here. Now let's keep
this very very fundamental and basic.
Let's just pass in one input. Let's call
it something like
message and obviously we put colon and
the we specify the data type of that uh
attribute. Now obviously the data type
of message will be string right so
that's why we specify strl again this is
just normal python so once we've done
that we are now going to be coding our
very first node again another very
fundamental element in langraph so how
do we actually define a node it's quite
simple it's just a normal standard
python function and this is how you do
it so let's say let's first try to find
The objective um let's say we are trying
to let's a greeting message a simple
greeting message. So we'll write def
greeting node and we need to pass in an
input and pass what the output type
should be. Now the input type of a node
needs to be the state and the output
type also has to be the state because
remember the state keeps track of all of
the information in your application
right so obviously you need to pass that
as an input and you need to pass out the
or return the updated state. So here's
how you do it. You pass in state and
what is the state of our application?
Well, it's the agent state which we
defined earlier, right? And the output
is going to be agent state cuz we need
to output the updated state. And our
updated state will again just be the
agent state once we've done all of the
um all of the mechanics we do in this
function, the actions we perform in this
function. All right. Okay. So now we
need to do something very very important
and it gets annoying sometimes but um
it's really a key habit which I want you
to form and it is dog strings. Now dock
strings and lang graph is quite
important. Why? Because dock strings is
what will tell your AI agents when we
actually build the AI agents your LLMs
what that function actually does what
that function's actions are what it
performs. So in this case uh by the way
to create a dock string is just three
quotation marks three pairs of quotation
marks. Uh let's call the dock string in
this case let's just write simple node
that adds a greeting message
to the state. Perfect. So now how do we
actually refer to this message? Well
again this is just normal Python code.
So we will pass in state and we will
type in message.
Now this specific part allows us to
actually update the state or the message
part of the state. And let's say let's
come up with something like hey
plus state
message. Um we can also add something
like how is your day going something
basic. Now what's the last thing which I
need to do in this function? Think about
it. Okay. So now remember in uh a few
moments ago I said we have to return the
state or the updated state. Well the
updated state we've already done we've
just manipulated the state here. So all
we have to do is just simply return the
state. Cool. And yeah that runs without
any errors. Okay. Now let's actually
build the graph uh which is again
obviously very important. So how do we
build the graph? Remember here I said
state graph is a framework that helps us
design and manage the flow of tasks as a
graph. Well that's exactly what we're
about to do now. So hopefully it clicks
now. So to create a graph in lang graph
you use the state graph attribute and
you pass in your state. You can see the
state schema which VS code has uh asked
for what uh the description of what the
parameters are. So our state schema in
this case is just the agent state which
we define right. So we pass an agent
state. I will actually also write here
our state
schema. So
uh you can physically see what it is.
Okay. And let's store this in a variable
called graph or something. Okay. Now now
here comes a very important method. How
do we actually add a node to this graph?
Cuz this graph is completely like
nothing right now. So to add a node we
use the inbuilt function graph add node
and it requires two main parameters. Now
what VS code is suggesting is a god I
don't even know what that all of all of
that is right it's very confusing. So to
put things simply you require really two
uh parameters the name of your node and
what action it will perform. So let's go
with the name. The name could be
absolutely anything sensible of course.
Um let's call something like
greeter. Cool. And you can see VS Code
has also asked us to um input an action.
Now what's the action going to be? Well,
the action will just be whatever your
node will actually perform. And what
action or mechanics will this node
actually perform? Well, all of that is
defined by this function, right? The
greeting node function. So we simply
just put that the name of the greeting
node function here and that's it. We've
successfully added the greeting node to
our function to our graph and it will be
named as
greater. So remember this
diagram in this diagram there is
supposed to be a start and an end point.
We've done the node which is sandwiched
in between these but we haven't really
added the start and the end point yet.
So, how do we do that? Well, there's
actually multiple ways to do that. In
this subsection, in this graph, I'm
going to teach you one way. Further down
the line, I'll teach you another way.
So, but they're both they're quite easy.
So, you simply just call the inbuilt
function set entry
point and as the parameter is just one
parameter which is the key. Now, the key
is the name of your node which you want
the start node to connect to. Again,
visualize it. The start the start point
is here and the node is here. Obviously
you need to reference a node for it to
create like an edge right. So we simply
pass greater and similarly graph dot set
finish point. We will again pass greater
here as well. Why? Because imagine again
the node is here and your finish point
is here and you need to connect some
sort of connection between these two
right and that's why we use uh greater
in this case. Don't worry, you will
solidify this once you complete the
exercises and as we go down building
more graphs. All right. And one last
thing which we need to do is actually
compile this graph. So graph compile
using the inbuilt uh graph using the
inbuilt compile function. And let's just
store this in a
variable. Cool. So that run without any
errors. But just a word of caution here.
Just because the graph compiles without
any error doesn't mean it will
successfully run. I mean, God knows once
we build like more complicated graphs,
there could be so many logical errors.
So, that's just an important thing to
know. So, don't get too happy once it
compiles cuz there might be logical
errors. Trust me, I know. Okay.
So, I want to write some code which will
actually help you visualize this. And
you can use the IPython library. So, you
can use this uh this um piece of code
here.
This code is awfully familiar with the
first ever graph I showed you, right? I
I'll put a picture somewhere here for
you to compare. The only difference is
really the name of the node which we've
set. In this case, it's greater. Why is
it greater? Because that's the name we
gave to this node, right? Cool. So
that's looks pretty good. Let's actually
run this. So to run you use the inbuilt
method
invoke. Um so let's pass in the message
as something like Bob or something and
let's actually store this result in a
variable. Okay. Now how can we actually
specify uh how can we actually get the
value of result?
So result we need to actually reference
a certain attribute. Now the only
attribute we have in uh the entire graph
is message right. So we simply just put
message and perfect you we get the final
answer which is hey Bob how's your day
going now why is it like this because
this is exactly how we set our act how
we set our function to be what action it
performs it says hey then concatenates
the uh input message in this case it's
just the name and it says how's your day
going now I could have changed this to
absolutely anything else right uh what
goes here like these functions are
almost endless but That's the whole flow
of how everything works. So hopefully
you understood how to build this very
first hello world graph. It's quite
simple. But um don't worry if you didn't
fully 100% understand this. I'm now
going to show you what exercise you need
to complete uh to be able to solidify
this. All right. All right. I'll see you
at the
exercise. Okay. So time for your very
first exercise. So the exercise for this
graph is quite similar to what we just
did, but I want you to create a
personalized compliment agent. So you
should pass in your name as like
something like Bob or something and then
output something like Bob, you're doing
an amazing job learning langraph. And to
give you a hint as to what you need to
do again, you again have to concatenate
the state, not replace it. All right,
it's very similar to what we just did
and it's quite basic. You should be able
to do this, but um this is really just
to get your hands dirty. All right.
Okay. Once you've completed this
exercise, join me when we build the
second graph. I'll see you
there. Okay. So now we're about to build
our second graph as you can see here.
And it's again quite similar to the
first graph we built except now we're
going to be able to pass multiple inputs
as you can see here. So again, what are
the objectives which you will be
learning in this? Well, we're going to
build a more complicated agent state.
Uh, and we're going to be creating a
processing node that performs operations
on list data. So now we're about to see
how we can really work with different
data types apart from just string. And
we're going to set up the entire graph
that processes and outputs these and
computes these results. And we're going
to be able to invoke the graph with the
structured inputs and retrieve the
outputs. But the main goal which uh I
want you to be able to learn in this
specific subsection is really how to
handle multiple inputs. All right. Okay.
Let's code
this. Okay. So now let's actually code
the second graph up the second
application up. So again I've just
imported the same things again the type
dictionary and the state graph. And I've
also imported the list this time. But
list is just a simple data structure
which you should know already. So if you
remember from the previous graph we made
we are supposed to uh implement the
state schema first right. So how do we
do that? Again we use the class agent
state uh type
dictionary. Okay before I continue just
a heads up I could have named the state
schema anything I want. I could have
named it uh something arbitrary
completely like a bottle for example. In
this case I've just said agent state
because one that's how I learned it.
It's like a habit for me now. But it
also really tells you what it actually
is. It's the state of your agent, right?
So that's why I've just kept it like
that. But again, just a heads up, you
could have named this whatever you want.
Cool. Okay. So now let's the if you
remember the main goal for this graph
for this uh building this graph was to
be able to handle and process multiple
different inputs, right? So how do we
actually assign and I really do that?
Well, the answer is in the state which
is here's what uh which is what we're
about to do now. So you really cuz
remember this is just a type dictionary.
So you basically have multiple keys now
you uh create that. So let's say
something like
values list integers.
So let's say one of our input is a list
of integers and let's also pass in a
name which will obviously be in a string
and let's have the result in a string
something completely random. But now you
can see we're now operating on two
different types of data structures uh a
a list of integers and a string. And
we're handling three different uh
different uh uh inputs values name
result. Okay cool. So let's run this.
Perfect. So now let's actually build our
node because in again in this uh graph
we're just going to have a single node
to keep things easy. Remember step by
step. So let's call let's write dev
process values and again what was what
needs to be
here? Yeah. So we need to pass in the
state and we need to return the updated
state. So how do we do that? Well, we
write state agent state and we pass out
the agent state. Cool. Now, again,
building healthy habits. I know it's
annoying. We have to write the dog
string. So, let's just write something
like this
function process
handles multiple
different value in multiple different
inputs. Cool. Again, I'm not being super
specific here because one, uh, I don't
want to spend too long on writing
doctrines and everything, and two,
there's no AI or LLM here, right? So
that's why it doesn't really matter. I'm
just doing this to build healthy habits.
Okay, so now let's do something like
whatever values we pass the list of
integers. Let's sum them up. And let's
also concatenate the name as well and
store it in the result. Sound cool?
Okay, so how do we do that? We pass in
state result cuz that's what we are uh
the action we're performing is on result
uh the attribute result and let's say
something like hi
there and then we refer to the name
um cool and your sum is equal to and
let's just use the inbuilt Python
function sum and we pass state
values cool and lastly we obviously
return the
Okay, perfect. And that's that done.
Okay, so now we actually create the
graph. Again, this is going to be very
very similar to what we did in the
previous section because again there's
just a node, there's a start point and
an endpoint. So like last time, we use
the state graph to initialize a graph
and we pass in our state schema. So
agent state and let's store this in the
variable graph. Okay. Uh let's add our
node. So graph add
node and again remember it requires two
parameters. It requires the name and the
action. So in this case the name will be
let's call it processor for example.
Again this could be anything you want
and your action will be performed by
this function right process values. So
we can just add that. Okay. Now I've
already told you how to uh how to
initialize a start point and an end
point and this is just given by that
code. So you attach your entry point to
your node. In this case it's just one
node which is the processor node and
again same goes with finish and you
compile it using
graph.compile. Perfect. So take a moment
now. How do you think this graph will
look
like? That again like I said very very
similar on how the graph actually looks
like but the only difference now is the
name of the uh node which we've kept
this as processor. Okay. So now let's
actually test this. Let's actually
invoke this graph. So how do we do that?
Well, we use the invoke function. Now
here's another important part which is
quite a common mistake especially like I
have done this many times. Make sure to
store your compiled graph in a variable
cuz if you invoke the graph i.e. if you
write something like graph.invoke that
won't make sense cuz you haven't
compiled the graph. That's why you need
to uh invoke using app. That's why I've
also done app here. If I did graph get
graph. Oh, it's completely messed up.
Right? It says state graph object has no
attribute because your graph hasn't been
compiled yet. That's why when I do
appget graph the uh process works. Cool.
So now let's again store this in uh
let's store something like answers is
equal to app.invoke. Cool. Let's pass in
some values. Let's say something like
values and let's have a list of
integers. 1 2 3 4. Again, I'm just
trying to prove a point. I'm not trying
to make a very complicated um graph yet.
And let's pass the name as something
like
Steve something. Okay. Uh cool. And
let's print let's print answers. Let's
see what
happens. Perfect. So now you can see
your values is 1 2 3 4. Your name is
Steve. And your result is Hi there
Steve. Your sum is equal to 10. Again,
why? because that's exactly what we uh
asked the node the action to perform. Hi
there, your name which in this case is
Steve. Your sum is equal to the sum of
the values and 1 + 2 + 3 + 4 is 10.
Right? And that's how you get this
answer. Now what if I wanted to just
access result? I didn't want any of this
other uh
nonsense. Well to do that you can again
just specify result and you will get it
in a more clean manner.
Cool. Okay. Now I want to try one more
thing just to build your understanding a
bit more. Uh let's put some print
statements here. So let's have a print
state
here. Then we perform the action and
then we print the state here. This is
really just to show you how the state
gets updated and it should be easy like
interpretable cuz this is quite a basic
piece of code. Again, print stated
before the action and print state after.
So there
cool and here you go. So value is equal
to 1 2 3 4 name is equal to Steve and
these are the inputs we passed. Now
notice I didn't pass results as an input
as well. I could have uh done that but
Langraph automatically sets that as like
a a none value in this case if you don't
pass an
input. Now here's where you need to be
cautious. If I had actually used state
result here as well to uh update state
result like I used state result to
update either itself or something else
then you would run into a problem
because your state result has been
initialized as none because you didn't
pass it as an input. So be mindful of
that. But in this case it worked because
we're only assigning state result. We're
not using it to assign something. It's
getting assigned. Cool. And you can see
after the action has been performed uh
your operation has been performed and
the thing has been concatenated. You can
see result is here and that was exactly
what we were getting before we cleaned
this up. Cool. So hopefully you
understood that. Again it should have
been quite intuitive and interpretable
but um to solidify your understanding
even more complete the exercise. So I'll
see you at the exercise
then. Okay. Welcome to the exercise,
your second ever exercise. And for this
exercise, I want you to create a graph
which passes in a single list of
integers along with a name and uh an
operation this time. And if the
operation is a plus, you add the
elements. And if a well times, you
multiply all the elements all within the
same node. So don't create an extra node
yet. So for example your input should
could be jack sparrow your values 1 2 3
4 again and then your operation uh uh
multiplication and your output should be
in the format of hi jack sparrow your
answer is 24 so just to give you a hint
as to how you would perform something
like this uh you would need an if
statement in your node so slightly more
complicated but the whole concept is the
same so once you've completed this
exercise I will see you in when where we
build this third graph All right, see
you
there. Okay, welcome to your third
graph. So, what are we going to do this
time? Well, enough processing multiple
values and everything. Let's actually
get the graph more complicated. So,
that's why we're going to be building a
sequential graph. So, all it all that
basically means is we're going to be
creating and handling multiple nodes
that can sequentially process and update
different parts of the state. So we will
learn how to connect nodes together in a
graph through edges of course and we're
going to invoke the graph and really see
how the state gets transformed as we uh
progress through our graphs step by
step. So again your main goal is should
be to understand how to create and
handle multiple nodes in langraph.
Sounds cool. Okay I'll see you at the
code. Cool. So now we're about to code
up the third graph. Uh, and we're making
quite fast progress. So well done on
that. So again, the imports are the
same. State graph and type
dictionary. Perfect.
And like we've done in the previous two
graphs, we're going to be coding the uh
the state schema or the agent state
first. So let's have class agent state.
And again, it needs to be in the form of
a typed dictionary, right? And in this
case, let's have the three attributes as
all strings because we've already we
already know how to handle multiple data
types, right? So, let's keep it simple.
Name string, age string, and final
string.
Okay. Now, here's what we're going to
build. Now, we're about to build our two
node functions,
uh, which are again the actions. Okay.
So again you simply write first well
I'll name it first node in this case and
like I mentioned before we pass in the
state and we return the updated state.
Okay. So again healthy habits doc string
again. So this is the first node of our
sequence. Okay. And what do we want to
do in this specific node? Well, I really
just want to manipulate uh the final
part. So, let's say something like
state final is equal to state or let's
have an f string
f state name.
Let's say something like
hi
that. Cool. And we'll just return the
state. Perfect. And now again we create
a new node. So state agent state. Return
that. Perfect.
And I'm just going to copy this dock
string and just change it. This is the
second nerf. Perfect. Okay. To speed
things up. And in this case I also want
to have state final is equal
to you are
state
age years old. Again quite a simple
example easy to follow. That's why I've
kept it as quite a basic graph. I mean
it's not going to solve the world's
problems or anything but it will help
you understand.
There is one logical error which I've
put deliberately here. I want you to try
to identify
it. Okay. So the logical error in this
case is the that once we've built our
graph and everything what would have
happened is we would have said hi to
whoever uh we pass in let's say Charlie
or something. So, hi Charlie. And we
store that in the final uh attribute in
the state, which is what we want. But
here's where things get like start to be
well logically incorrect. Once we
finally get to our second node, again,
we're updating state final, which you
can do. You can repeat, you can um
interact with these attributes at in in
any node possible in all of the nodes.
And you can do it as many times as you
want. But notice this part. What's
happening here is we've completely
replaced all of the content we had
before. So remember how we had hi
Charlie? We've just completely replaced
it with you are age years old. But we
want both of them both of those stuff,
right? So how do we get both of them?
Well, again we just concatenate them. So
we can have something like
state
plus state file. And there we go.
Logical error should be now solved,
right? Cuz now we have concatenated
state final. Uh we're essentially just
like adding on to uh we're preserving
what we had before, right? Okay. Now
let's get to the fun part. How do we
actually build this graph? And really
it's quite similar to the previous two
graphs except there is one new thing
which you're about to learn. So like
always we use state graph to start the
framework. So agent state and let's
store it in
graph. Again I could have had this name
the width variable into anything. I've
just kept it graph cuz it makes
intuitive sense. Okay. Now we add our
nodes. So we do graph add node. And for
simplicity sake I'm just going to have
the name as the same name as the uh
function. Okay. So that way it'll just
be easy to follow. So graph add
node and second
node. Second node. Cool. Okay. Now that
we've added both nodes, we need to
obviously s uh add the entry point and
the end point, right? So we set the
entry point like this. Again, quite
self-explanatory because we wanted to
connect to the first node, not the
second node, right? So it should be
start uh first node, second node, end
point. How do we connect the first node
and the second node together
though? Hopefully you had an answer for
that. Uh if you remember or recall from
the previous section, theory section,
there was an element in Langro called
the edge. That's exactly what we're
about to do right now. We're about to
use edge and that was the new thing
which I was talking about a few moments
ago which you're about to learn. So how
do we use it? Well you use graph edge
add edge and if we can hi perfect. So
again it's quite simple you use a start
key and end key. So sim similar to entry
point where but your in this case you
need to pass two parameters. So the edge
we want is between the first node and
the second node right? Well that's
exactly what we pass here. So first node
and second node and like before we will
just set the finish point at second node
and we will compile this. Now how will
this graph look like? Take a moment to
try to think of how it will look
like like that. Start point end point
and these two notes are sandwiched in
between. But now there is a
edge. It should be called a directed
edge if I'm being like quite picky. But
yes, a directed edge cuz the flow of
data or your flow of your state updates
is from the first node to your second
node. Right? Cool. So now that we've
built that, let's again invoke this. So
I've got this code ready here. Uh let's
invoke it. Let's pass the parameter as
Charlie and let's pass the age as 20.
Cool. Print
result. Perfect. Apart from the uh
misalignment here which I can just
change right
now. Perfect. Okay. So now you can see
it says hi Charlie you are 20 years old.
Now obviously we could have performed
all of this in one single node which we
have been doing in the previous
subsection but the obviously the aim was
to be able to create multiple nodes
right and handle um the state how the
state progresses. So yes you one
important thing which you've learned is
obviously how to use the add edge method
but another concept which you have
solidified here is you can uh change
these at these keys of your state at in
at any point in time like as long as as
however many times you want cuz remember
here we've passed in state final um we
implemented state final here we
implemented state final in the second
node if we had more nodes in the
sequence. We could have done that again
and again and again. And we also learned
how to like one key logical error is
sometimes a lot of people just
accidentally replace uh their content in
one of the attributes and that leads to
a lot of logical errors. So always be
mindful of that. And yeah, that again
was quite simple, not too hard and
hopefully the exercise which I'm about
to give you solidifies this. Cool. So I
will see you at the exercise then.
Awesome. So now we will move on to the
exercise for this third graph. And what
I want you to do is really build on top
of what we just covered. Instead of two
nodes, I want you to build three nodes.
Again, in a sequence, don't need to go
too fancy yet. We will again three nodes
in a sequence. And we will have you will
need to accept the user's name, their
age, and a list of their skills. So the
first node will be specifically for
personalizing the name field with a
greeting. The second node will be
describing the user's age. The third
node will be listing all of the user
skill in a formatted string. And then
you'll need to combine this and uh store
it in a result field and output that.
And this should be a combined message.
And the format I would like you to
output is something like this. So let's
say the name was Linda. And let's say
Linda welcome to the system. You are 31
years old and you have skills in Python,
machine learning and langraph. Okay. And
just as a hint for this exercise, I
would you'll need to use the add edge
method twice. So this will really
solidify your understanding on how to
build graphs in general. All right,
cool. So once you've done that, again,
answers will be on GitHub for all of the
exercises. Once you have uh cross
referenced and checked that you've done
it right, I will see you in the next
section where we build our fourth graph.
All right, see you
there. Welcome, welcome, welcome. Okay,
I'm particularly excited for uh teaching
you this graph, graph 4. Why? Because
we're about to learn how to build a
conditional graph. So for the very first
time, we're about to implement
conditional logic. And obviously we've
done it in a previous exercise before
but that was within a single node. This
is how to implement conditional logic in
the overall graph structure. And so we
will be implementing conditional logic
to route the uh flow of data to
different nodes. We will be using the
start and the end nodes to manage entry
and exit points. We will be designing
again using multiple nodes to perform
different operations such as addition
and subtraction. And we will be able to
create a router node to handle
decision-m and control the graph flow.
So the main goal is really to you how we
can use this inbuilt function which uh
allows you to create conditional edges
in langraph. All right, exciting stuff.
I'll see you at the
code. Okay, so let's actually code this
up now and you'll see the imports are
slightly modified this time. Again, type
dictionary and state graph is there. But
now I've also imported start and end
point. Again, if you remember a few
subsections ago, I told you there are
multiple ways to be able to initialize
the start and the end point. And this is
another way you could. Arguably, this is
the easier way, but um whatever. I don't
really have a preference, but I'll teach
you both ways regardless. Okay, let's
import these. Successful. Okay. like
standard procedure we will design we
will um code up the uh the schema the
state schema so class agent state and
let's again type dictionary in this case
uh uh I want to be able to pass in two
numbers and pass in an operation so a
plus operation and a minus operation one
of those two operations now obviously I
could have handled uh all of this within
one single node But that's not the point
here. I've kept it deliberately very
very simple. So the main concept which
you learn is how to uh implement
conditional logic. Okay.
So let's code the different uh keys
which we require. So number one will be
an integer. Operation will be in the
string a plus or a minus. Uh number two
will be an integer and final number will
be an integer. the final number will be
the result of either adding or
subtracting the two
numbers. Easy enough. We've done this
multiple times now. Okay. Now, here's
where things get interesting. Now, just
a heads up. Initially, this won't make
sense. But when we look at it from a
bird's eye view and we look back at all
the code in this subsection again, uh
everything will start to click. So
again, it won't make sense initially,
but it will once we look at it. Uh
again, don't worry. All right. So let's
create our first node function. Let's
call it adder. And it's again still a
node. And we input the state schema. And
we return the updated state schema and
dock string again. But uh this time I'm
just going to copy it from here. Uh it's
tells exactly what it does. This node
adds the two numbers. Uh and easy
enough, we just do state final number is
equal to state uh number one plus
state number two. Okay. And we just
return the
state. Quite simple, right? And just
like what we did with the addition, we
need a node for subtraction as well. So
def subtractor. Now uh I already
implemented it to uh don't to not waste
time but this node subtracts the two
numbers. It's very similar to the
previous uh node function. Uh it just
subtracts these two numbers. Again yes
you could be saying what if number one
is uh smaller than number two it'll give
you a negative result. It that doesn't
matter. The main aim again was to
implement the conditional logic not the
um inner workings of each node. Okay.
Okay. Now we built another type of node.
Uh and we initialize it the same way but
this time let's call this node decide
next node. Let's actually give it a name
which actually says what it does. Right.
So again we use state agent state and we
pass like this. Perfect. Okay. Now the
dock string will be something like so.
So this node will select the next phase
of the graph or well next node of the
graph I should say.
Okay. Now we use an if statement and
before I code something let's just try
to map how this will work. This specific
node will be at the start of our uh
graph. So we will have the start node.
We will have this uh this specific node
we'll call it the router. and this
router because it routes uh the next uh
to the next node depending on what the
state schema is at that point. So we
will have the uh I will put an image up
right now so you kind of get what I'm
trying to say but we essentially will
have the router decide whether we uh add
the two numbers and subtract the two
numbers and obviously this will be
decided with the operation uh attribute
right which you should see from here.
Okay, let's code this up now. So this is
not the hard part. If state operation,
if I can spell if state operation is
equal to equal to
plus. Okay, if state operation is equal
to equal to
plus, we need to do a certain thing to
pass it to the next node. Okay, now
here's well your first guess could be
okay. Well, we guess I guess just call
this function, right? Not exactly. Not
in langraph. You actually return
uh return the edge. Now, we haven't
described the edge yet, right? But for
now, I will just say the edg's name is
addition operation. So, addition
operation. Similarly, if it's
subtraction, we will do this like so. So
just to reiterate we will uh you we will
see what the um value is at the
operation in the state schema. If it's a
plus we call we will return the edge
addition operation and if it's a
subtraction we will use the subtraction
operation edge. Again we haven't
described or defined these two edges
yet. That's what I was saying earlier.
When we look at it from the bird's eye
view later on in a few moments once
we've built everything it will make much
more sense. So stick with me for now.
Okay. And runs perfect. Now we build the
graph. And now here's the exciting part.
So we again like normal standard
procedure we use state graph to create
the graph framework. So graph is equal
to
that. And let's add these nodes uh to
the
uh to our graph. So graph add
node and let's say
router. Okay. And again we will pass
this decide next node. Perfect.
Okay. Now I have another confession to
make. Lots of conventions. I know this
won't work. I know I haven't built the
rest of the graph yet but this
eventually will not work. And there is a
subtle reason why this won't work. You
know, it's mainly in this line. Add node
router decide next node. The problem is
with decide next node cuz oh, you can
see that the dock string appears once we
press uh the decide next node. But the
reason this won't work is look closely
at these three functions. What are we
doing in these two functions that we're
not doing in this?
I'll give you a moment to try to analyze
this. Okay. So, doesn't matter if don't
worry if you didn't get that. The
correct answer is we are returning this
updated state in this one and this one.
But in this node, we're not. We're just
returning the edge. Subtle difference I
know but that's how Lang graph works and
you will see why they do it like that
uh right now. So how do we deal with
this? Now I obviously could have built
this graph and then I would have shown
you the error but then things would have
just gotten messy. That's why from the
get- go I have told you why this
wouldn't work. So now that you know why
this won't work, how do you fix this?
Simple. You use this code lambda
state. Now, if you have used lambda
functions before, this is quite easy to
understand. If you haven't, don't worry.
All this is saying is your input state
will be your output state. That's it. In
even more simpler words, think of this
as a pass through
function. So, what it's saying is your
input state will be passed, your state
will be inputed and your output will be
the exact same state. Now, why is it the
exact same state? because you're not
changing the state at all. You're
comparing stuff here, but you're not
assigning anything. There's a difference
between comparison and um and
assignment. Right? Again, even in this
one, you're just comparing to see
whether the operation is a minus, but no
assignments been made at all. In fact,
there's been no changes to this state
whatsoever. That's why we can use this
as a pass through
function. Now, hopefully that made
sense.
Okay, let's continue. Again, we will get
a lot more practice. Don't worry, this
is the first time you're seeing this.
Okay, so now we will add the edge. And
this is just the normal edge we did last
time. So, we will need the start key.
And now here's how you initialize
differently. Remember how we used to do
set entry point and set finish point? We
don't do that anymore. Uh we use start
the keyword cuz that's what we imported.
Make sure to import it if you do it this
way. uh you use start and end. So your
start will be a start point and your
what do you want the start to be
connected to? Well, we want it to be
connected to the
router. If I put this in quotation
marks, perfect. Now, why not add node or
subtract node? Well, think again. Refer
back to that diagram which I'll show in
right here.
We if we connected the start point to
the the add node or the subtract node,
well then what's the point of the router
in the first place, right? The whole
point was the router decides what the
inputs are and then from there it
branches off to the correct node. So
that's why the router needs to be the
first node we uh connect our start point
to. Cool.
Okay. Perfect. Now we add the we now
implement the main the new thing which
we are going to learn in this section is
graph dot add conditional edge. So graph
dot add conditional
edges. Now again wow looks really
confusing but it's actually much more
simpler than it looks
like. So the first uh part is your
source which you can see here as well.
So the source will just simply be the
name of the node. And what's the name of
the node which we want the conditional
edge to be? It's the router node, right?
So that's going to be the source part.
Perfect. Now if you look here, it's
asking for a path. What's the path you
would like it to do? Now before we
implement the path, we obviously need to
per uh imple uh tell it what action what
what action it needs to do. And that's
where this node will come in the decide
next node part. So we pass that as the
second parameter. So that's the
path. And now we implement something
called the path map which you should
have briefly saw
here. Uh there path map. So we've
implemented the source which is the
router. We've implemented the path which
is your uh decide next node function. Uh
again don't need to worry about hashable
runnable any and all of this stuff.
Okay, it's you don't need to over
complicate it. Now it's time for the
path map. Okay, so now your path map
will be in a form of a dictionary. And
remember how I said earlier that we had
implemented addition operation and
subtraction operation. These were edges.
So now we're about to implement those
only. So we're about to create two new
edges here. Let me just write this code
up for you and then it will make sense.
Give me one second.
Okay, so there we go. Now what is this
code actually saying? Well, this is in a
format of
edge and
node. Now the starting point of this
edge will obviously be this router node
and it's telling us where it will
connect to. This uh visualization will
be it will be it'll be much easier to
visualize when I actually show you the
graph. Don't worry. But for now,
addition operation and subtraction
operation is the edge. And the two nodes
are add node and subtract node. Right?
Okay. Uh lastly, we now we're now at the
point where we need to create the end
point. But obviously, we if you look
back at this diagram which I've shown on
the screen right now, you can see that
the we need two edges to connect to the
end point, right? We need to we need an
edge from the and node and we need an
edge from the subtract node. So we can
add two edges like this. graph
edge. Uh we uh start at the add node and
then we end at the endpoint. Again
similar subtract node and endpoint. And
then we just compile this. So app is
equal to
graph.compile. Cool. No errors. Okay.
Now here comes the most exciting part.
Again try to visualize what this graph
will actually look
like. Okay. So it should look something
like
that. Probably slightly different to
what you initially anticipated but
that's okay. We again have a start
point. We have the router and we have
the our two nodes add node subtract
node. And notice remember when I said
addition operation and subtraction
operation are the edges names. Well,
here it is. Addition operation and
subtraction operation. It's telling us
uh what the which direction to go into.
Do we go how do we go to add node? Well,
we use the addition operation. How do we
go to subtract node? Well, we go to the
subtract operation. And then obviously
we create these two
edges, these two to connect to the
endpoint. Awesome. So, we will once
again look at it from a bird's eye view.
But let's actually invoke this graph to
see what happens.
So let's use this piece of code. So what
it's saying is it's defining number one
as 10, operation as minus and number two
as five. So because we've used
subtraction, the final number should be
10 - 5 which is five. And we've printed
the results and the answer is like such.
Uh number one is equal to 10, operation
is equal to minus, number two is equal
to 5 and final number is uh five.
Obviously the way I've invoked it is
slightly different to what I have done
before. Again, this is another way you
can
invoke. Okay, so not too hard. But let's
just go through everything one more time
to solidify everything. Okay, so we
imported everything. We created the
state schema using agent state and a
type dictionary. Then we created our
three different nodes which is the add
node, subtract node and the decide next
node. And this is in within the decide
next node. You can see that if the
operation is a plus, it goes to the
addition operation edge which is this
edge. And if it's subtraction operation,
it goes to this side. And this is how we
built the graph. We added the nodes. We
added the edge from the start point uh
to the router. And then we added the
conditional edge. the new thing which
we've learned in this section uh which
is we uh reference router and we use the
edge node format. So the edge will be
addition operation uh to add node then
it will be subtraction operation to
subtract node. Visually speaking it will
be addition operation to add node
subtraction operation to subtract node.
Now, I know this will be quite confusing
at first and don't worry, it took me
quite a while to understand this myself
as well, but hopefully the exercise I've
given you will really be able to help
you understand this much better. Okay,
so I will see you at the exercise
then. Awesome. So, let's actually find
out what the exercise is for this graph.
So, you need to make this monstrosity.
Now at first glance it looks terrifying
but if you analyze it a little bit
closer all it is is what we just coded
twice. So we coded this and we need to
replicate it once more. So in essence
you need to actually input four numbers
and two operations and you need to
output their final results. For example
number one, number two, number three,
number four and the respective operation
and the respective results. Right? So in
this case we would have to do 10 - 5
which is 5 and 7 + 7 + 2 aka 9 and those
two numbers should be outputed. Now the
reason I gave you this exercise to do is
because this will really solidify your
understanding about conditional edges
which will really be important for the
next few next graph and the next AI
agents we make. Okay. So once you have
uh completed it by looking and cross
referencing the answer on GitHub, I will
see you in the next graph.
Okay. All right. Well done. We're almost
at the end of this section and we're
about to build our final graph aka graph
5. Now we've learned quite a lot about
Langraph and its internal mechanisms.
And this will really help us in the next
section where we finally build the AI
agents you were looking for. Now in this
section in this subsection sorry we're
going to be learning an important
concept. There's still one more concept
we haven't learned and that's about
looping. So we're going to be creating
well a simple looping graph. Now I kept
the objectives to be quite small here.
There aren't that many objectives. It's
essentially implementing logic uh which
involves looping uh to route the flow of
data back to the nodes. And we're going
to be creating a single conditional edge
which you know how to do in the previous
section. Regarding the previous section,
however, I know the exercise. Please do
complete that exercise. That exercise
will be probably the hardest exercise
you would have done until this point.
So, don't worry if you didn't get it. If
you did, great job. You're doing really,
really well. But if you didn't get it,
look at the GitHub. Try to compare where
you went wrong. Remember, in Langraph,
there's more than one way of building
the graphs. Make sure the graphs are
well built and it actually functions.
And if you want an extension, try to
make it even more robust than it is. All
right, but back to this now. Final
graph, I promise. The main goal really
is to code up the looping logic. So,
with that out of the way, let's build a
final code for this section. See you
there. Awesome. So, final code we have
to build for this section. And here we
go. So, graph 5 squ. Now, I'm going to
take a slightly different approach this
time. And I'm actually going to show you
the graph we want to end up building
from the get- go. And there's a reason
I'm going to start that from now so we
get in good practice. The reason is once
you finish this course and actually
start either making your own AI agentic
systems for someone else, for your
clients or for yourself like make your
own JavaS system or whatever. You
obviously need to plan how it works,
right? You need to see okay, what nodes
do I need? What edges do I need? Does is
this does this need to be a conditional
edge? where's the start point going to
go, end point going to go etc etc and
you can either do that via pen and paper
or software like I've used but point is
you need some sort of blueprint and
that's how really it works in the
industry as well um you can you will
obviously have a blueprint and then from
there you will code up the graph similar
to how a UI designer for example uh
renders um their UI designs and then
sends that off to a software developer
who uh well develops the application
forwards. Right? So that's the habit I
want to start uh creating with you. All
right. So this is the graph I want to
build in this section. So there's
obviously going to be a start and end
point. And this really should be mostly
familiar except for this loop. So there
we're going to create a simple greeting
node and another node which is called
the random node. So in the greeting note
I essentially want the user to have uh
stated their name and it should output a
simple hi there your name and then the
graph progresses to the random node and
in the random node I essentially want to
generate five random numbers. Okay, now
just as a heads up, yes, this graph in
industry would be completely useless. I
know, but I've deliberately kept it
simple again so you know the
fundamentals. Like this loop is could
have easily been avoided and transferred
into a for loop for example, right? Like
I could have had a for loop within this
node and ran it five times to generate
the numbers. I get it. But this is again
kept deliberately simple so you actually
understand the concept. Okay, cool. So
let's the usual inputs and the only
difference is this time I've also
imported random but if you have used
Python before quite a lot you would have
come across this library right okay so
let's start with our agent state so
class agent state type
dictionary and what's the first thing
we're going to need well let's see we
have the start point do we need anything
any keys that no for greeting note what
did I say I want uh I wanted the user to
be able to input their name. So, we need
a name attribute or a key. And then for
the random number, a random node, we
need some form of um a list to like
actually store the numbers. So, we have
number and list
int. Okay, cool. And one more thing,
look at this loop. How will we actually
know when to stop? We need some form of
counter, right? So, counter int.
Perfect. Now, obviously, just as a heads
up, when you do go on to make your AI
agents and everything, you're not going
to know what attributes you need right
from the get- go, unless if you planned
it like extremely extremely well. But
chances are you won't get it. But don't
worry, iteratively well, you'll
obviously be better at speculating what
attributes you need through practice.
But you can obviously do iterative
development as well, right? Okay, cool.
So now let's actually build these
nodes. Okay. So let's start off with the
uh greeting node. So how we normally
define uh a function. So def greeting
node, we obviously need the agent
states like such. Perfect. And the dock
string. But uh luckily for me, I've
already got that here. So I don't need
to do it again. I know it's boring, but
habits. Now let's update update the uh
name uh key. So how do we do that? Well,
you should know by now state name is
equal
to let's say something like hi
there. State name.
Perfect. So what will this do? I input a
name and it'll replace that name with a
string of hi there this person. Now
let's also initialize the counter
variable here. Now why am I doing that?
Let me just first write it and think
about this.
Okay. Now, obviously I'm changing I'm
setting like the value. So, I will need
to have passed in like an valid integer
when I am passing the uh value when I'm
invoking the graph, right? But here's
the thing. What if I pass in minus2 for
example?
Well, as the counter value, as the
initial counter value, if this line
wasn't there, well, it would have just
kept on incrementing until it got got to
five cuz I want to have five numbers.
But if it starts at minus2, well, it
would end up giving me seven numbers.
Now, that's not robust, right? So, this
basically wipes out whatever rubbish
integer the user even inputs. If they
had put zero, well, okay, we replaced it
to zero. If they put like minus 20
because they're greedy or something,
then we have made sure to like set that
back to zero. So, so just a way to make
it robust. That's all. Uh, return state.
Okay, cool. So, now let's create our
second node which is a random node. So,
we can say random node state agent state
agent state. Perfect. Dog string.
Again the dog strings will be useful. I
promise in the next section they will.
So this generates a number random number
from 0 to 10. Now this piece of code
here
essentially appends the appends the
randomly generated number to the number
list. Okay, that's all it does. And what
else do we need to do in this node?
Well, we need to increment the counter
value, right?
So C uh plus equals to one. So this will
increment uh the value by one and then
we just return the
state. Okay, cool. Now here's where
we're how we're going to implement the
looping logic. Now just a warning here
and please listen to this. Like in any
software development uh program or
programming language G2, there's more
than one way of coding up an
application, right? Same goes with
Langraph as well. There is multiple
multiple different ways of coding like a
looping code like this graph. I'm going
to be showing you one of them. I
obviously can't show you all of them cuz
there it's just time constraint, right?
But obviously the more you practice the
uh uh better ways you'll more efficient
ways you'll find, right? But the way I'm
going to show you is pretty efficient as
well. Don't worry. Okay. Now, you might
have speculated that I'm going to create
like a router node. It's close. I'm not
going to create another router node. You
can see in the graph the uh the client
let's say the client wants this graph.
The client doesn't want another router
node here. So how do we go about that?
Well, we could create a conditional
edge. How do we do that? Okay, let's
begin that. So let's write a new
function say defaf should continue
uh state agent
state agent
state and um let's create this block
string um function to decide what to do
next something like that. Okay cool now
here's where we set our looping logic
and this should look quite familiar to
you
now. Perfect. So let's run that. Okay.
So what have I written here? Well, if
the counter value is less than five
because we're starting with zero, right?
So 0 1 2 3 4. That'll be five values. Um
I've also written a print statement so
like we can keep track of um um the
progress. Also whenever I'm writing the
code as well when you're uh coding with
me or doing the exercise, it's really
helpful to print uh statements uh like
put in print statements everywhere. Or
you could also use break points as well.
So you know uh where to where the code
failed if it
fails. Okay. So here we return the loop
a loop edge and the exit edge. So
obviously we have the loop edge and this
will be the exit edge. So everything is
going to plan so far but um so far is
the key. You never know, right? Okay. Uh
just as a heads up though, I want to
show you this. So this is how the
trajectory should follow. We start at
the greeting node. Why? Cuz we obviously
go from the start to the greeting node.
And then we enter the random node. And
we enter the random node and exit it
five times. So 1 2 3 4 5. Why five
times? Because we want five random
numbers, right? By then this if
statement will uh well it won't work. It
will fail. So we will go to the else
statement and return exit. And if we
return to exit, we'll go to the end
node. Uh okay. endpoint. Okay, so that's
how the general gist is. Okay, let's
quickly make this graph. So you should
know how to initialize a graph agent
graph and let's just add these nodes. So
we have our two nodes which are
here greeting and random which is
exactly what we wanted, right? Greeting
node and random node. Perfect. Okay. And
now we're going to add an edge between
greeting and random. Uh why? Because
well I've created this edge. You see
this edge greeting node and random node.
This edge that's the edge I've created.
Okay. Now I'm going to create the um the
conditional
edges which is done through
here and I've written some comments here
as
well. So uh there will be the source
node which is the random. So where I
want the conditional edge to start from
and then the routing function or this
tree I should have really written action
here because is the action I want to
perform the underlying mechanism or
function which is going to which we're
going to um determine which edge to use
and that's uh implemented by the should
continue function right and notice how
again these two edges are the same edges
here. So if the loop is uh the one which
um uh is outputed then we need to go
back into its random the random node
which we've generate uh which we put
there and if it doesn't we go to the end
part. Okay and then obviously we set the
entry
point. Okay. So again you don't have to
set the exit point here uh or the finish
point because we've already done it
using end here. Okay, perfect. And then
we just compile the graph app is equal
to
graph.compile and okay, it compiled.
That's a good sign. But let's see if we
have got our graph to be the exact
same. Now I'll put the graph image here
so I don't keep scrolling back and
forth. But you can see we have the start
point and the end point. We have the
greeting and the random. And then we
have our two condition edges. So we have
the loop going back into the random node
as we wanted and the exit which you can
see. So take a moment and you can see
compare and contrast. Okay, let's
continue. Okay, now I have this
code. So I've given a name my name uh a
r um a completely brand new list and
I've set counter to minus
one. And as you can see it enters loop
one, loop two, loop three, loop four
because these are print statements we
printed. Uh it says hi there v which is
my name. Uh number 10 21026 just
randomly generated and you can see the
counter value is five. Now remember what
I was saying over the counter. We set
the counter value to zero here to make
it more robust. If we had not done that
well it would have generated six times.
And now I can set this to minus 100. it
will still obviously give me different
random values but um the code is largely
the same. So that's really the way which
I personally use to create loops in
langraph it's pretty easy right but um
obviously with practice you might even
find some other ways if you do find
other ways like obviously uh do let me
know uh there's more than one way again
you can send me a message on LinkedIn or
Instagram or whatever but um yeah so
this is finally finally uh we have
implemented the code for our final graph
of the section
So just complete the graph 5 exercise
please and yeah we should be good to go
to make AI agents. So I'll see you at
this codes exercise. Okay
cool. Okay good job on that. Now for the
exercise for this last graph uh you need
to implement this graph on the right. So
you need to implement an automatic
higher or lower gain. So for context,
you need to set the bounce which we can
guess between 1 to 20 integers of course
and the graph has to keep guessing where
the max number of guesses is 7 where if
the guess is correct it stops but if not
we keep looping until we hit the max
limit of seven. Now please note we don't
have to pass any inputs the actual graph
should automatically guess by itself. So
there should be no human in the loop
human intervention at all. So each time
a number is guessed the hint node aka
this node should say either higher or
lower and the graph should account for
this information and guess the next
guess according accordingly. So for
example the input should be something
like the player name student. The guess
should just be an empty list cuz we're
initializing the list. Attempts should
be set to zero and the lower bound and
upper bound should be 1 to 20. Now the
reason I've also passed these as inputs
is because uh if you wanted to expand
this to maybe 1 to 50 numbers or
whatever you can. It's quite easy to do
that. So just as a hint uh it will need
to adjust it its bounds after every
guess based on the hint provided by the
hint though. So once you've completed
this exercise you would have fully
reinforced uh your understanding about
loops in langraph. So once you've
completed this, cross reference it.
Cross reference the answers on GitHub. I
will see you in the next section where
we finally begin AI agents. See you
there. Okay people. So welcome back to
this brand new section where we actually
start learning about AI agents. Now we
finally are upgrading our ability in
Langro. I even upgraded my clothing
sense. Not really. But this is exciting
times cuz we actually finally build AI
agents. So, we're going to build a lot
of AI agents in this section. And
starting off with the first agent. Well,
technically it's not really an agent,
but I just named it that because it
sounds cool. But um technically it's not
though. But let's see what we're going
to actually learn in this section in
this subsection. So, we're going to
build a simple bot. That's it. And these
are the objectives. So we're going to
define a state variable uh state
structure which we're going to have a
list of human message objects and I
briefly uh me uh mentioned what a human
message was uh a long time ago in the
course. Uh what it is it's well it's in
the name it's a message prompt which is
given by the human aka us to the AI. Uh
we're going to initialize the GPD40
model for this uh using lang chain's
chat open AAI uh uh library. Uh we're
going to send and handle different types
of messages. We're going to build and
compile the graph of the agent. But the
main goal really is how we can integrate
LLMs into our graphs. So what is this
sort of graph we actually going to end
up building? Now it's very very simple.
It's going to look like this. And yes,
this looks exactly like the graph we
made in the uh first ever graph we
actually ever made. But um the
functionality will obviously be
different cuz now we're actually
integrating LM. So exciting stuff
people. Uh okay, I will see you at the
code
then. All right, coding time. So now we
first code our well we code up our very
first AI agent aka the simple what and
um I've already imported all the
necessary libraries we'll need uh to not
waste time. So while you're uh coding
these up as well and copying these I'll
also briefly explain what these are so
we're at the same level. Okay, so we've
already imported type dictionary and
list many times before but um these two
we haven't sorry these two the lang
chain codon messages import human
message so I briefly mentioned this in
the intro of this section of the
subsection what a human message is right
and this is the library we get it from
and similarly we're going to be using
openai's lms so that's why we're going
to use chat openai from the lang chain
open aai uh library uh the
langraph.graph. Uh these we were
familiar with and this is the env. Now
just a few points. You could have been
saying okay wait hold on I thought we
were about to do a langraph stuff. Why
is the lang chain stuff here? Now you
must know that langraph is built on top
of lang chain and lang chain already has
the sophisticated libraries right so why
not actually use them that's how
langraph is designed it's designed to
use the robust sophisticated libraries
which lang chain offers right so no I'm
not a trader we're still doing langraph
stuff but we're also using leveraging
lang chain strengths as well okay and um
now this env file now it's okay if you
haven't ever um encountered av file
before. Essentially, it's just a file
used to store secret stuff like API keys
or configuration values. So, it's really
there for security purposes. Now, I have
my own
um file stored in my folder structure uh
so that you don't see my API key uh
because if you do then I would go
bankrupt. So, that's why. Now, you might
also be wondering why do we need an API
key here? We need the API key because
we're doing calls to an external LLM. If
we were using our own LLM like through
OAMA, then we would um not have an API
key, right? We would just use like the
Olama library integration with lang
chain. So because we're using charges,
we need an API to communicate with the
LLM in their cloud servers. Cool. So how
do we actually load this? So to load our
um API, we just use a simple Python uh
code load. Env. All right. So now that
we're at the same level, let's actually
code up our AI agent. Cool. So let's
define the state like we always do. So
this time class agent
state type
dictionary. Perfect. Okay. Now what are
the attributes we need in this section
uh in this uh state? Well really just
one the messages part right so messages
but what form will it be well it will be
in the form of a a list of human
messages right so we'll have list human
message why because we when we invoke
the graph we're inputting human messages
right so to tell the large language
model that this is a human message I i.e
Uh this is a message from me the user
aka human right. Um we need to actually
mention human message that it's a human
message type. Cool. Okay. So now we
actually initial initialize the large
language model. So we just write lm is
equal to chat openai. And now we specify
what model we want. Now I'm going for
GPD4er. Now yes there's also chat uh
anthropic. I think there's chat oama. Um
there's a lot of like in-built um
libraries which lang chain offers which
is great. Personally I've used chat
openai a lot. I've also used chat
anthropic a lot as well. Uh personally I
like chat openai cuz it's just really
simple to use. I've also used tried well
tried to use chat oama before but really
there's some difficulty in integrating
it with lang. So that's why I've opted
for openi. And if you're worried about
financial cost, don't worry, it's
extremely cheap. Uh if you want, you
could also go for the GPD 40 mini model
as well if that's a concern. But trust
me, it's extremely cheap. Like the input
tokens, output tokens is like in like
tens of pennies for like a,000 tokens.
So really, really cheap. Okay. So now
let's actually define our node through
our function. So
process and we obviously define the
state and then
return the state like so. Perfect. Now
how do we actually call the lm? Now lang
chain and the langraph team really like
using the word invoke. You might have
noticed that to call a graph or like to
make the graph run we've used invoke.
Similarly to run the lm we use invoke as
well. So we okay let's store the
response we get in a variable. So uh
lm.invoke and what do we invoke? Well,
you can see from the uh hints here that
it requires an input of language model
input. What's that basically saying is
what what what do you want the LM to do?
Right? What's your question? Now what is
our question? Well, that's in the
messages. So we write state messages. So
what will happen here is as soon as I've
written state messages, let's say I have
written hi or whatever uh we will pass
this to the LLM through the invoke
method. The LLM will then generate a
response from its cloud server through
our API and it'll get it will give us
back the um its response and then we'll
store it in the response section uh the
response variable. Cool. And um let's
actually print
this like so and return the state like
such. Okay, done. Now we obviously need
to create the graph like such.
Okay. So uh what is it saying? Well,
it's saying that there is we've created
a node process which is that which where
the action is the process function. The
add we've added an edge. We've added an
edit from the start to the end node end
point and we've compiled the graph.
Okay. Um yeah. So let's now ask the for
the user input. So user input is equal
to input. We'll say enter
something. And now we will invoke the
agent cuz we need to invoke the agent of
course because we're creating a graph,
right? And the graph is well like agent
in this case. Cool. Let's actually run
this code now. So, Python
agentbot.
py and perfect. So, enter. Let's say
hi. The AI message was hello, how can I
assist you today? Now, I can reassure
you I did not pre-code this or hardcode
this. This is the actual LM. Let's run
it uh one more time.
Let's come up with a different message
like who are
you and it'll say I'm an AI language
model created by open AAI called chat
GBT. So you can this basically pretty
much confirms that yes this is GBT uh in
the background. Okay, but
um why why just stick to one message,
right? Why not uh be able to run
multiple message like asking multiple
messages kind of like a chatbot, right?
So this is the code which does this and
I'll walk you through this what's
happening here as well. So uh like
before we input our query and now we
basically say keep iterating through and
as soon as the user has said like exit
or something then uh well you exit the
while loop and that basically signifies
that well you don't want to talk to the
ailm anymore. So let's have get run
this. So python agentbot
py. Okay let's say hi again. Hello how
are you? But now we can run it again.
It's just a simple y loop. It's nothing
groundbreaking. So like who made
you? Okay, perfect. What is 2 + 2? 2 + 2
equals 4. Okay. Uh let's say now, hi, I
am
Bob. Okay, now watch this carefully. I'm
about to ask what did I
just well or I should say what is my
name?
I'm sorry, but I don't have the ability
to know your name or any personal
information about you. Why is
that? Why didn't it know what my name
is? Well, even though I clearly
specified it. So, let's quickly
exit. Okay, now this is important.
Nowhere in the code have we actually
created some sort of memory. That's why
I called this
subsection simple bot. And that's why I
kept on saying AI agent because it's not
even an agent yet. Uh it's just a simple
like the most basic LLM wrapper you can
possibly have. But at least now you know
how to actually integrate
um LLMs in your graphs, right? And it's
pretty straightforward. You just you um
you just uh embed them within your
functions and then your functions
obviously act as the actions in your
notes. And that's it. It's quite an easy
piece of code. Like it's only what 29
lines or 25 lines give or take. Uh but
yeah, pretty simple. Um I don't think
there'll be any exercise for this cuz
well there really isn't much to do with
this. So I will see you in the
introduction for the second AI agent
we're going to build. Okay. So I'll see
you
there. Cool. Cool. Cool. Okay. So now
we're going to build our second AI
system. And we're going to try to fix
the problems we faced in the last uh AI
system we built. And what was the
problem? Well, the problem was it
doesn't remember what we in what we had
said before, right? Why? Cuz we were
calling separate API calls. So now we're
going to try to create a chatbot with
some sort of memory. That's why I
included the brain emoji here. So let me
walk through the objectives for this uh
subsection. So, we're going to use
different message types in particular in
particular the human message and the AI
message. We're going to maintain a full
conversation history using both of these
message types. We're going to
particularly use the GPD4 model again
using the lang chains uh chat open AI
library and overall we're going to
create a sophisticated conversation
loop. So, what is the main goal goal of
this um subsection? It's really to
create a form of memory for our agent.
So if you're ready, let's go to the
code. All right, awesome people. So
let's begin coding our simple chatbot
then. Okay, so like last time, I've
already imported all of the uh necessary
libraries and it's largely this exact
same except now I've added two more uh
stuff. So the first is the AI message
and I explained this in the introduction
of this subsection why we need the AI
message. And I've also imported the
union type annotation. Now the union
type annotation is something we covered
in the first chapter. So if you if this
is the first time you are looking at it
or hearing about it, I would recommend
you going to the first chapter really
understanding and watching the first two
chapters. They're quite short to be
honest and then coming back. Okay. Now
that being said, let's actually begin
the uh coding then. Okay. So like
always, we define the state. So class
agent state
uh typed dictionary. Perfect. Now last
time what did we define this as? Again
we're only going to have messages again
but uh last time we had list human
message. Okay so that was what we had
defined as our agent state
previously. Now this time we also want
to include the AI message as well. We're
building a more sophisticated chatbot.
So how do we do that? Well, one way or
the naive way is to really have it as
messages
AI list AI message or something like
that. Something like that. And don't get
me wrong, this is still a valid
approach. You can still build your graph
and everything like that, but um I think
it's a bit longer. So let me tell you
another way which would actually be
better. So remove this. Instead, let's
use the type annotation union like this.
So,
union like so. And let's include AI
message. Now, what has this done?
Essentially, let me first tell you about
a bit about human message and AI
message. Human message and AI messages
and like all of these like different
structures are actually data types in
Langraph and Langchain. That's what the
developers of these libraries have got
them to be. And um when I write union
human message AI message then that
basically allows me to store uh either
human messages or or AI messages in this
uh key in the state the messages. So
that's what that literally means in a
nutshell. Now, one important thing which
I want to mention is this. All of these
AI agentic libraries like Langchain,
Langraph, Crew AI, Autogen, they're all
great, but um you really can make your
own AI agentic system by writing just
Python functions. You don't even need to
use a library. Now that being said, I
would still recommend using these
libraries, especially Langraph because
Langraph, well, because it's a personal
favorite, no bias at all, but um it's
Langraph really allows you to control
much more than other libraries would.
Obviously, not as much control as if you
were writing the Python functions
yourself and everything, but I think
it's a good balance of how much control
you have and how much uh unnecessary
jargon you need to write. Because think
about it, think about how much of um
this unnecessary code which you would
have had to write else otherwise uh
langraph and lang chain support. So
that's why I highly recommend using
these libraries and everything. So again
human message and AI message are data
types inbuilt data types within uh lang
lang graph and lang chain. Cool. Okay.
Now let's again initialize the large
language model as we did last time. And
again we're only we're using GP4.
Okay, now we're going to create our
node. Again, it's going to be the exact
same graph structure, by the way. So,
state agent state, but obviously the
actions we perform will be slightly
different. Now, um let's write a dock
string. This node will
um this node will
uh
do solve the request you input
something. Dog strings aren't really
needed for this AI agent or this
subsection because we're not going to
use them. But um again, good habit.
Okay, cool. Let's invoke
this. So what have I done here? This is
exactly the same code which we did in
the previous subsection. The l we invoke
the lm uh with the state messages. And
what are the state messages? Well, it's
could be either human message or an AI
message. It's a list of those. Awesome.
So now we write this piece of
code. Okay. State messages.appen AI
message content equal to
response.content. What on earth is
happening there? Okay. Let's break this
down. Response. Well, that's just
extracting only the content part of the
response aka the response being the
answer or the result after we make the
uh API call from the large language
model. And it only extracts the content.
So it only extracts like the important
stuff, right? It removes all the
unnecessary jargon which comes with it
like the amount of tokens you use and
all that. It removes that and that's uh
gets stored in that gets converted to to
an AI message and that's appended to our
state messages um in the state. Simple.
Okay. Uh now obviously to make it look
pretty in the terminal we're going to
print this and then we're going to
return the
state. That's it. That's how simple it
was.
Okay, so now we're going to create this
exact same graph. And that's why I've
just copied and pasted it because it's a
time waste of me rewriting the code in
front of you again and again. So we can
just reuse the same code because it's
the exact same graph uh graph structure
as the previous subsection. Cool. Okay,
now we're going to now here's where it
actually starts working differently.
See, last time we didn't have this the
conversation history. really this is
what's going to be our memory in in um
this uh setup. Okay, so we have now in
initialized conversation history. Now
again we're going to ask the user what
they want, right? What's their request?
So now we use this Y loop and this Y
loop was the exact same loop we had in
the previous subsection as well. uh it
only exits unless if the user has uh
inputed well exit obviously but now look
at this the conversation history is
appended with the human message and the
human message is obviously the user
input the reason I've kept on writing
content is because well that's the
parameter in human message as you can
see
here okay cool uh and we've invoked the
agent what is the agent well the agent
is the compiled version of the graph the
compiled graph uh with uh the entire
conversation history. Now this is
important. The entire conversation
history is sent, not just the current
human message. So uh this will make more
sense. Don't worry, I'm um trying my
best to explain it right now, but
obviously it will make much much more
sense as soon as I start running it.
Okay? So bear with me if you didn't
fully understand that. Don't worry.
Let's remove that for now.
Uh, and then we replace the conversation
history completely like wipe it with the
result messages. Why? Don't worry, it's
going to make sense as soon as I run it.
And I think yeah, we should be able to
run this now. So, let's
write python memory agent.py, which is
the name of the
file. Cool. Okay, let me just quickly
write a hi just to see if the API is
working. It is perfect. Okay. Hello. How
can I assist you today? Uh, now I'll say
like, "Hi, my name is
Steve." Hi Steve, it's great to meet
you. How can I help you today? Okay, now
remember from last time. Last time if I
asked it, hey, who am I? It didn't know.
Do you think it will know
now? Think about
it. It does. you are Steve or at least
that's the name you've chosen to share
with me. Uh and the rest is yes
whatever. So it does know about what I
have said but just looking at this code
I guess you can try to like pick out
okay how does it work and everything
like why everything works like that but
um I think we can add print statements
and everything. So let's try to add
print statements now and see well how
this is actually working. So let's exit
the program.
Okay. Uh let's add a print statement
here. Let me include this. Cool. So what
is this saying? So this print statement
actually kind think of it like a
snapshot of what the current state is.
So as soon as it goes into a process
note as just before it's about to finish
by returning the state, we also print
the current state as well. And this will
literally just output whatever is stored
in the messages attribute within our
state. Okay. So let's clear. There we
go. Let's run this
again. So hi, nice to meet you.
Something like
that. Now take a look at the current
state. See it outputed hello, nice to
meet you. How can I see you today? Why
did it output that? Well, because in our
process
function it we've asked it we formatted
it in a way so it says hey AI which is
this part and the response or content is
this part. Okay. Now this response or
content is also what was stored remember
how I said it's stored in the um in a
nice manner and was appended to our
state messages. Now was it appended to
the state messages? Yes. How do you know
that? Because look at the human message.
The human message was what I wrote which
was hi nice to meet you. Uh forget the
additional keyword arguments and
response metadata cuz I didn't provide
any. Uh you don't need to worry about
that. The main part is this part the
content. And then look at the AI message
part. Uh it's the content is equals to
hello nice to meet you. How can I see
you today? Notice how it's the exact
same thing as it was
here. Okay. Now, now we're going to go
one step ahead and I'm going to ask it
to
say my name is Steve again. Now, think
about how will this current state
change? Pause the video and try to think
about
this like that. Okay. So, now the second
uh message I sent was my name is Steve.
Its response for the second message was
hi Steve. How can I help you today? Now
look at the current state. It still
begins with hi, nice to meet you, which
was the first ever message I inputed
into this conversation and then its
respective AI message. And then that
gets uh appended. Why appended? Well,
because we had appended the AI message
and appended the human
message. So that's why. Okay. And you
can see the human message is my name is
Steve which is the most recent uh
message which I put and then the AI
message which is hi Steve how can I help
you
today? Perfect. And we can just keep
going and going and going. But uh for
now I'll
exit. Now here's the thing. This works
well relatively well, right? We've got
it like as a chatbot which is what we
wanted. it has some recollection of
memory or or like of what we what we are
who we are and everything. But there's
two big problems here. Let's start with
the first uh massive problem which is
this. You know how I've exited the
program right now. Yeah. Okay. I'm going
to run the exact same program
again. Now I told it that my name is
Steve. What is my name?
and it
says uh I'm sorry I don't have access to
your personal data. Okay. And look at
the current state completely wiped out.
Again, that's pretty self-explanatory as
to why you exited the program and that's
why obviously all the var the data was
stored in the variables, right? The
state was stored in the variables
completely got wiped away. So what is
the solution? Think about it.
Well, obviously one potential solution
would be to store it in a database, like
a large database, right? Or a vector
database if you're trying to do some
ragged applications. For now, I'm just
going to store it in a very simple text
file. Why? Cuz it's really easy. And
I've got the code as well. And usually,
honestly, I just store it in a text file
when I'm prototyping. Now, yes,
obviously, storing it in a vector
database or a database is much more
robust and sophisticated, and that is
what you should do. But when you're
prototyping and you want to really see
uh try to build it quickly and fast, uh
I just tend to use a text file. It still
works uh still works great and
everything. So what is the code for the
text file? Uh it's
here.
Okay. So what is this code saying? Well,
essentially it's saying create me a text
file called logging as a as a text file
you see in write mode and a file. Write
your conversation log. This is just to
like make it look better and more
aesthetic. But this is the main part of
the code which um you should actually
try and understand for every single
message in the conversation history.
Okay. Now note the conversation history
was this variable which we had like
initialized the conversation history uh
stores the AI messages and the human
messages. So that's where all of the um
the information outside the graph
actually is. Right? the state is locked
in within the graph now and uh the
conversation history is just another I
guess you can say a duplicate version of
the state right because we've you we've
appended the exact same human messages
and AI messages and kept on updating it
through this line cool so what it says
is that for every single message in the
conversation history by the way a
conversation is the duration between my
first message and the last message I
sent that entire thing is a
conversation. A conversation isn't just
a single API call. It's the entire
length. Okay? So, just to be mindful of
that. So, uh it first checks if it's a
human message, it writes that as you and
then extracts that content and if it's
the AI message, it uh puts it under the
AI stuff. So, let's run this again. So,
let's exit this. Clear this. Okay.
Who? Okay, let's say hi, I am Steve.
Again, I'm using Steve because a
Minecraft movie just came out, so that's
why. Okay, now I'm going to
intentionally make a spelling mistake
here. Good morning. It should obviously
morning should have been spelled, right?
But I'm doing that for a reason. It gets
no problem. Let's say tell me a joke.
Just another random thing. Sure. Why
don't skeletons fight each other? They
don't have the guts.
Um, really rubbish. My point is it
works. Now I'll exit the program. And
now it says conversation saved to
login.xt. Now look at
this. Remove that. Let me remove that.
Okay, perfect. So this is the
conversation log. The first message I
ever sent was, "Hi, I'm Steve." There,
it's response. Now, good morning. Now,
why did I spell it like wrong? Why did I
do that? Because I wanted to show you
that this is the actual human message,
my message being stored unaltered. So
whatever I pass in the state as a human
message that stays there. So it's
unaltered. The AI message cannot or or
anything can really change the previous
human messages at all. Right? So that's
why. And you can see tell me a joke.
Sure. It's it's a rubbish joke is after
that. And that's the end of the login.xt
file. So that's a really fast efficient
way, not the most robust way of course,
but it is a fast efficient way to be
able to store your data outside um the
application if it stops. Perfect. Now,
what was the second problem that I was
mentioning? It's
this. Look at how I initially I say,
"Hi, I'm Steve." I don't know why I
printed twice there. Weird, but
whatever. Look at the current state
length.
Okay. Then I pass in another message, it
becomes longer. I pass in another
message,
uh it gets longer. It keeps getting
longer and longer and
longer. That's a problem because think
about it, you will use these uh library
uh you'll use these like large language
models whether it's for your own AI
agentic startup or your own mini Javas
or your own projects or whatever it is.
You would obviously want to minimize
cost, right? But using so many tokens uh
using so many tokens like input tokens
especially will really eat away uh your
uh the amount of money you will uh spend
like it will drastically increase it and
that's a huge problem right we want to
try to be conservative a bit about our
money and our financial our finances so
what is one what is a way to solve this
think about
that Well, right off the bat, I can give
you an easy solution to implement which
is within the code, write it, write some
code where if the number of human
messages exceeds five or something like
that, then you remove the first human
message in your uh history. Why remove
the first and not the latest? Well,
because the latest is most likely to be
more relevant, right? The first message
could is most likely to be the one where
um the one which is well not needed or
it could have been like it can it has
more of a chance to be like a bit more
less of an impact to have been removed.
So why did I pick five? Well, five is
just a random number I thought of. You
could do 10, 15, 20, 25, three,
whatever. But that's a really easy
solution to do. Okay, so we learned
quite a lot there. We learned how to
integrate human message and AI message
within a thing. And now we've created a
somewhat of a sophisticated chatbot,
right? It has a memory. It still talks
to us. We if we define uh if we write
who we are, it remembers that and
everything and it works great.
Obviously, it has its flaws, but for
now, it's pretty good. Okay, so now
we're going to build our third AI agent.
And this is going to be a special type
of an AI agent.
The technical term for this type of
agent is called a react agent and react
stands for reasoning and acting. So this
is a quite a common type of AI agent
which you will build. So how does it
look like? Well, it looks something like
this. So it's quite simple. There's a
start point and then it's an end point
obviously. Then you have your agent and
then we use a loop where we attach it to
tools. Now, this could be one tool, two
tools, a lot of tools. And it's the
agent's job or the LLM in the background
to be able to decide which tool to
select. But not only that, it's all it's
also its job to be able to decide when
there's no more tool calling left to do.
And when that happens, it goes to the
end part. So that's the general gist of
what a React agent is. It's a very very
common and famous type of agent to make
in Langraph. And that's exactly what
we're going to be building in this
subsection. So what are the objectives?
So to build a react agent, the
objectives are learn how to really
create tools in langraph. We're going to
be creating a react graph. Of course,
we're going to be working with different
types of messages such as tool messages.
See, last subsection we've we covered AI
messages, human messages, but now we're
going to look at a lot more types of
messages. for example, tool messages,
system messages, base messages, and
we're obviously going to test our
robustness um of our graph. So, the main
goal is to create a robust React agent.
So, if you're excited, I'll see you at
the
code. Okay, people. So, now we're going
to code up the React agent. And just a
heads up, this is going to be quite a
long subsection. So, get ready. You can
see it's going to be long because of how
many imports I've done. But because I've
done so many new imports, I actually
want to take some time off and really
explain each line so that we're all on
the same page. Okay, let's go. So the
first line is from typing import
annotated sequence and type dictionary.
Now we obviously know what a type
dictionary is, but we haven't come
across annotated or sequence yet. So
these are also type annotations. And
I'll start off by explaining what an
annotated is. So annotated is a type
annotation which provides additional
context to your uh variable or your key
without actually affecting the type
itself, the data type itself. Now what
exactly does that mean? Well, I'll give
you an example. Let's say I am trying to
create a type dictionary where there is
an email key in it. Okay? Now, obviously
an email is string. So if I was to
create a type dictionary, I would have
written email colon string, right? Sl.
That's how we've been doing it. But
here's the thing with certain keys like
email, they have to be a certain uh
format. But like for example, it has to
be like
abcgmail.com for example. But if I pass
in
abcd-gmail.com or something like that,
that's not a valid email format anymore,
but it's still a string technically. So
it would pass through. So how do we
resolve that? Well, that's where
annotated comes in. And I'll give you an
example here. Let's say email is equal
to annotated. I'm not going to create
the whole type dictionary to save time.
But for uh the example itself, you first
pass in what data type you want it to
be. So we want email to be a string,
right? That's not changing. But here in
quotation marks, I provide some more
additional information, additional
context. And this is basically adding
onto the metadata of this key or
variable. For example, uh let's say this
has to be
a valid email
format. Now, obviously, I should do it
in more detail, but um that's how uh for
now, that's fine. So, how how can I
actually see the metadata? So, if I want
to, I would write print
email metadata
uh like that. And then I would press
run. And here we go. You can see this
has to be a valid email format. That's
the exact same thing which is which we
wrote here. So that's annotated done.
But what about sequence? What does
sequence mean? Well, sequence is also a
type annotation. And the way I've
described it is here. It basically
automatically handles the state updates
for sequences such as by adding new
messages to a chat history. Now what
does that mean? Well, it's really just
there to avoid any list manipulation to
the graph nodes. Obviously, like when
we're using graphs and nodes and all all
of that stuff and updating the states,
there's a lot of uh list manipulations
which we'll have to do. Sequence really
handles a lot of that. So, that's really
what it's there for. You don't really
need to uh worry about it too much.
Okay. Now, if we continue, we have env
uh from import loadenv. From last time,
we know that this is just to store our
API keys and I've done that here. That
will load the API keys. But you'll see
now these three uh imports. We're
importing some new message types here.
So we're importing base message, tool
message, and system message. I'll start
off with the tool message. So it's
essentially a type of message where
where the data is passed back to the LM
after the tool has been called and like
the information which is passed is like
the content itself, the tool call ID. Uh
that's what tool messages. It's pretty
self-explanatory. Now for a system
message, it's the it's a message for
providing instructions to the LLM. So
like for example, if you've used uh LLM
APIs before, you might have written you
are a helpful assistant. That's exactly
what a system message is. And don't
worry, we're going to code this up as
well. So you'll actually see what they
are. Now what's a base message? So in
the comments, you can see that I've
written the foundational class for all
message types in Langraph. Now here's
how this works. Think about the class
hierarchy. So you know how you have a
parent class and then you have child
classes as well. Well the base message
would be the parent class and these uh
AI message, human message, tool message,
system message and all these other types
of message will be like the child
classes and they will inherit all the
properties of the base message cuz
that's the parent one. I guess you can
say the uh all father or something but
the AI message, human message and all
these child uh classes obviously they'll
have their own properties, right? For
example, the tool message has its own
content and tool call ID and all that
stuff. So that's what the base message
is. It's really the foundational class
for all the message types in
Langraph. Cool. Okay. So now if we
continue, you can see we've imported
chat, openAI. Uh we've done state graph
and M. These we've come across. We know
what they are. And we've imported tool
and tool nodes which we cover in the
second chapter or second section of this
course. uh these are different elements
which we're going to be uh using in
langraph. Now what about this line from
langraph dossage import add messages.
Now what does that mean? So this is a
little bit um different. This add
messages is a reducer function. Now if
this is the first time you're hearing
that don't panic. It's not that hard. So
let's let me copy this one second. Okay.
So a reducer function is essentially
just a rule that controls how updates
from nodes are combined with the
existing state. In simpler words, it
really just tells us how to merge new
data into the current state. Now here's
the thing. If we didn't have some sort
of a reducer function, uh updates would
have just replaced the existing value or
state entirely. And I'll give you an
example for this.
So let's say I had a state where it was
just high. I had one attribute messages
and high. Now obviously I should have
created the type dictionary and
everything and formalize it but just for
simpler um for times saving purposes
I've done it like this. Now what if I
had an update which says nice to meet
you. If I didn't have a reducer function
that would completely overwrite it. Now
in the previous uh graphs and agents
we've made we've appended it but now
that we're using so many different
messages and calls and tool calling and
what
whatever we can't really always append
everything like it will get far too
complicated. So that's why we need to
leverage reducer function. So if we
didn't use a reducer function it would
just overwrite it completely. But if we
did like hi nice to meet you it would
append it. That's the key. So in a
nutshell, the reducer function really
just aggregates the uh data in the
state. This reducer function uh and the
reducer function which I'm talking about
is add messages. So once again, add
messages is a reducer function that will
really just allow us to append
everything into the state without any
overring happening cuz so we want to
preserve the state. Okay, cool. So now
let's actually code this uh react agent.
Okay. All right. Okay. Okay, I've
cleared the screen now and let's
actually begin like we how we always
begin with the uh creation of our state
of our agent. So, type dictionary like
such. Okay. And now we we'll only have
one key in this uh in this example which
is just messages. And now let's use the
new type annotations we've learned. So,
sequence base message and reducer
function add messages. So again this
piece of code is saying to preserve the
state by actually appending it rather
than overwriting. That's what this
reducer function does. Okay. All right.
Okay. Oh, and the sequence of base
messages is the data type and this
provides the metadata. That's why we
have the annotated keyword here. That's
really it. Okay. Uh now let's create our
first ever tool. Now how do we do this?
Some of you who have a um who have come
from lang chain might know how to do
this already. We use a decorator and we
define like this. Now this decorator
basically tells Python that this
function is quite is special. It does
something and well it is special because
it's a tool which we're going to use. So
let's define our tool as def. Let's
create a simple addition tool. Okay. So
we'll say a integer b integer.
It's basically going to add two numbers.
And this is where doc strings actually
come now. And I'll show you how
important they are. For now, let's say
uh this is an addition
function
that adds two numbers together.
Okay. All right. And we just return a
plus
b. Simple. Now, how can we actually
infuse these tools to our large language
model? Well, first let's create a list.
Add like such. Now, yes, at this current
moment, I only have one tool, but in a
few moments, we'll have multiple tools.
That's why I'm adding this uh list for
now. And let's actually create our
model. So, model is equal to chat
openai. Model is equal to
GPT40. Again, I'm using GPD40 because
I've never had a problem with it to be
honest. So how can we tell our GPD40
large language model that these are the
tools you can use? Well, we can use this
inbuilt Python um inbuilt function
called bind tools. Bind tools like that.
And we pass in the list of tools we
have. So that's tools. Pretty simple,
right? Okay. So now large language model
will have access to all of our
tools. Okay. So now we need to create a
node which actually acts as the agent
within our graph. So how do we do that?
Let me create just a simple function
like def model call. We pass in the
state agent state. Again it needs to
return the agent
state.
Okay. Now I'm going to quickly copy this
piece of code. Give me a
second. Okay. So what is this code
doing?
uh you can see that we're invoking the
model aka running the model and this is
the system message which we are asking.
So we're explicitly saying the large
language model that you are my a system
please answer my query to the best of
your ability. So that's what the large
language model's task is to do. Now if
we want to get technical here, you could
have written it in a slightly different
way and that way is through
this. So remove
this. We could have said system
prompt. Okay. So what's going on here?
Remember how I said system message is
also something which we imported. Uh so
the system message like I said is this
line of uh is this line. You are my AS
system. Please answer my query to the
best of your
ability. Now, either way would have
worked if we if I had just straight up
passed this string into here. That would
have worked as well. Personally, I think
this way is better. Even though they
achieve the exact same thing, I think
this way is better cuz it's more
readable. Okay? And you're only adding
just one more import. Okay? So, I would
prefer you to I would really recommend
you doing like uh like this so even the
large language model knows that this is
a system message. Okay, cool. And this
is uh just another way of writing like
the updated state. You know how we've
been writing state uh brackets messages
is equal to something something
something. Well, this is a more compact
way of updating the state as well. So
return messages response. So we update
the messages with the response. No plus
equal to this this this or adding
something we just we can simply just
write it with the updated state. Why?
because the add messages aka the reducer
function handles the appending uh for
us. It doesn't overwrite it. Now, if I
ran this code and I built the graph and
everything, would it
work? No. Why it wouldn't work? Because
think about it, the response when we've
invoked the model and we store it in the
response when we actually invoked it, we
didn't actually pass in the query. How
do we pass in the query? Think about it.
All I passed is my system message. Where
does the query go? So to be able to add
the query, I actually have to add like
this. So state messages. The query it
will be in the form of a human message.
And the human message will be stored in
the messages attribute, right? And now
that we've passed that into our model as
well and we can invoke it. And now this
should work.
Okay. Okay. Okay, so now we define the
conditional edge. Now why do we need the
conditional edge here? I'll put the
picture of the react agent. Again here
you can see that the looping part even
like in the last one in the graph when
we made the loops for the first time you
saw that was it was a conditional edge
which we had to use and now that's
actually going to come in play here.
That's why I took so time to build those
graphs because now the concept is
coming. So how do we define the
conditional edge def should
continue. Okay. So again like always we
pass in the state and let's do it like
this like such else
return continue. Okay. So as you know as
you um might have guessed end and
continue will be edges which I'll define
later in the graph. But what is going on
here? Well essentially when I'll pass in
the query uh when we've invoked the
actual model you will know that we'll
create a list of tools right so what
we're going to be doing is we're going
to be uh getting the last message and
we're going to see if there's any more
tools needed to be ran. If there are
then we'll go into the continue edge aka
we'll go to the tool node and we'll
select the tool and we'll do all this uh
actions and then come back. If there's
no more tool calling left we will just
end and we'll just exit the uh graph and
that'll be the case. You'll get uh uh
you'll understand more what I what I
mean when we've actually test we're
testing and running the graph. Okay. Now
let's just define the graph. So like
always we create the graph we initialize
the graph through the state graph and
let's call the node R agent. So the
action will be the model call aka the
underlying function will be this.
Okay. Now we create something called a
tool node which is also what we covered
in the previous uh in the second section
or second chapter in this course. The
tool node essentially is just a singular
node which contains all of the different
tools. So we only have one tool. If you
see what this variable is tools, we only
have one tool which is add. Don't worry,
we'll add some more tools like subtracts
and multiply in a bit. But I just want
to uh like really solidify your concept
of how we can add these tools and how
the graph will work. Okay. Now we
obviously set our entry point and point
it to the R
agent. Now let's add our conditional
edge. So remember remember how I said
there's two edges, continue and end.
again continue and end and if it goes to
the end we end it. If it goes to tools
then we go to tool node which is
tools. Okay. Okay. So yeah this is
pretty straightforward still. Right now
we also need to add an edge which goes
back from our tool to our agent cuz
that's how we're going to create a
circular connection.
Right? You can see that the conditional
edge only provides a one-way directed
edge from the from either the agent to
the tool node or the agent to the
endpoint. But we need another edge which
will go back from the uh tool node back
to the agent. And that's what this um
that's what this edge does. And lastly,
we need to uh obviously compile it. So
we'll just say app is equal to graph
dompile. Perfect. That's it. Now I've
just created a a new helper function
here which this isn't part of langraph.
I've just written this code because it
will make every like the tool calling
and everything uh like output in a much
better way. So you'll see what I mean in
just one
second. Okay. So now we
actually can begin. So let's say the
input is uh something like this.
Let's say I want to add 3 + 4. Okay,
simple. And this line of code basically
streams the data. That's all it does.
So, let's actually run this. Clear. And
let's do it. Okay. So, remember we wrote
add
3+4. Wow, look at that. So, we've added
3+4. It calls the tool and it even knows
what tool to pick. Add. Um, and it gives
us the result. The tool message as you
can see is seven and the AI message the
final AI message is the sum of three and
four is seven. That's it. Let's try
something harder now. Let's write add 34
+ 21. So if we run
this you can see 55 cuz 34 + 21 is 55.
And you can also see again all the tool
calls and everything that's done right.
I want to show you one two more things
actually before we add some more tools
which is this. If I remove this dock
string here by commenting out for
now. Let's clear and let's run that
again. Error. Why? Because the function
must have a dock string if description
is not provided. The dock string is
necessary. That's why included otherwise
the graph won't work. It's remember it
tells the LM what that tool is for.
Okay. So now that we've have uh we've
got that there, let's try this as well.
Add
uh 3+ 4. Again, this time I want both of
them to be executed. So
clear now. Do you think this will work?
Let's
see. Add 34 + 21. Add 3+ 4. Perfect.
Brilliant. Okay. So you can see the
result of adding 34 + 21 is 55. The
result of adding 3+ 4 is 7. You can see
how the tool was called twice this time
and that's the power of the loop which
we created. Remember we created the
conditional edge and then we also
created that directed edge back from the
tool node to the agent. Let's let's try
to make it even uh give more um
complicated stuff. Let's say
add add 12 + 12 something. So let me
clear this.
Clear. Let's see what happens.
Wow, look at this. If I press enter,
sorry, I messed up there. But you can
see the results of the addition as well
as 34 + 21 is 55 7 24 or and you can
also see that I called the tool the
sorry the AI called the tool three
times.
Now these tool calls is also an
indication that the LLM didn't use its
own like information inbuilt information
which it was trained on to come up with
an answer. Right? Remember an LLM
doesn't know how to do maths. It just
guesses the next output like through
probability. But through this we were
able to actually add the two
numbers. So an important concept here is
the LLM actually decides what should be
passed as the arguments to each tool. So
3 + 4 like if I said add 3 + 4 it will
actually uh create it will actually uh
input the numbers 3 and four and then
this tool will handle the uh information
return it and it will go back to the
agent and then the AI agent will decide
what's the answer and everything. So
that's how it works. Awesome. Okay. Now
let's make this even more complicated.
Let's add some more
tools. Let's add
subtract and multiply. Okay. And the
only re change we have to do is instead
of this one line we just now include
subtract and multiply as well. That's
it. Otherwise this line this code
largely stays the same. Now let's
actually run this same command and see
if it gets confused with the different
um different tools we have it has access
to. Now let's see. Okay.
You can see
again that 55 724. Okay, it didn't get
confused. Perfect. Let's now give it a
different command. Let's say something
like this. One
second. Add 40 + 12 and then multiply
the result by 6. So now it has to make
use of two different tools. Let's see if
it gets
that.
Okay. Wow. Brilliant. So it first used
the add tool and then used the
multiplication tool and you can see all
the queries or all the tool called and
everything and the final answer is 312.
So 52 * 6 yes it is 312. Okay. Wow that
works like brilliantly. So now that we
know that this is robust what about if I
add this let's say also tell me a joke
please. What do you think will happen?
Do you think this will break? Let's see.
If I play this and run this. Let's
see. Wow. Look at
this. The result of 40 adding 14 and 12
is 52 multiplying that is by 6 is 312.
And here's a joke for you. Why don't
skeletons fight each other? They don't
have the gun. I swear to God, it's
always the same dead joke. But you get
the point. This is so robust. It can
handle even queries where it doesn't
even need a tool and that ladies and
gentlemen is the power of langraph. So
it's it's so robust even if we don't
need to use a tool it will still give us
an answer and the reason it was able to
do that is once all the tool calling is
done it passes it to the agent the agent
checks again oh I need to tell it I need
to tell the user a joke as well and adds
that to the final information and then
ends it that's the power of
lang okay so after all of that we
finally now know how to create a react
agent yes it was a simple react agent
but the concepts the same. You can
create your own external tools from now
onwards and you can create your own
graph. And that was the whole point of
this course, right? For you to actually
understand how we can uh create these um
how we can use different tools and then
the rest is up to you. It's up to your
imagination. Okay, perfect. So now I
will see you at the next subsection. All
right, see you there. Okay, people. So
we've made great progress so far. So
well done on that. But now we make a
fourth AI agent. And this time we'll do
things again slightly differently. Well,
this time we're going to be making a
mini project together. So the project's
name is going to be called Drafter. And
you'll see why in a minute. So picture
this. Me and you are working in a
company together. And our boss comes up
to us and she has a problem and some
orders for us. So the problem is this.
Our company is not working efficiently.
We spend way too much time drafting
documents and this needs to be fixed.
Again, a valid problem. So, what are her
orders? She says you need to create an
AI agentic system that can speed up
drafting documents, emails, etc. The AI
agentic system should have human AI
collaboration, meaning the human should
be able to provide continuous feedback
and the AI agent should stop when the
human is happy with the draft.
The system should also be fast and be
able to save the drafts. Okay. So then
me and you start discussing and we are
going to use land graph obviously and we
come up with a sketch. Now the sketch of
our graph is something like this. It
obviously is going to have a start and
an end point and it's going to have our
agent and the agent will have access to
tools aka the tool node. Now this looks
similar to a react agent which we
covered in the last subsection. But
there's a reason we don't we haven't
chosen to do that. See we realize that
one of the tools is the save tool. It
will save the draft, right? That was one
of our requirements. But obviously when
we once we've saved it, the process
should end, right? But if you remember
from a React agent, the tools always
goes back to the AI agent, not directly
to the endpoint. And we don't want that
anymore. So that's why as soon as the
save tool is used because the save tool
will be within tools right it ends. So
that is the structure we have chosen to
go with. So the only thing left is to
actually code this graph. So let's code
this together
then. Okay. So let's actually code up
this drafter project then. So you can
see I've already done all the imports
and I've loaded up my env file. Now all
of these imports are imports which
you've already uh encountered before. So
there's no point in looking at them
again. But the first thing which I'm
going to do is I'm going to be defining
the a global variable.
Now this global variable yes it's a bit
odd defining global variables and
there's a reason which I've done it and
this will become more apparent as I go
through the code but just as a heads up
the reason I've defined a global
variable in this case is to actually
pass in a state in tools the the correct
way to do it in langraph is through
something called injected state now
injected state is beyond the scope of
this uh course so the workound on that
is to use a global variable and what
will happen is our tools will uh
whatever updates are made uh we'll
update the global variable and then when
we go on to save it uh the save tool
will use the contents in this global
variable and save that into a text file.
So that's why this is included. Okay. So
now let's define our agent state again.
And the way that's done is the exact
same way we did last time. Uh class
agent state messages annotated sequence
base message add message as the reducer
function. So now we define the tools and
there will be two tools for this. The
first tool will be the update tool and
the second tool will be the save tool.
So let's start off with the uh update
tool and I will obviously use the
decorator and then create def
update and then we need to pass in
uh pass in a parameter content. Now just
as a refresher whatever parameters you
pass or you request who actually gets
those parameters? Well, the LLM or your
model in the background that's uh what
will automatically pass the parameters
for this model uh for this tool. So, uh
in this case the content parameter will
be uh that will be provided by the lm in
the background. So, you don't need to
worry about that. Okay. So, now we need
the dock string obviously and I've just
created a simple dock string which just
updates the document with the provided
content because that is exactly what it
does.
So now we define to interact with the
global variable in Python, you obviously
need to uh define it uh you need to code
it like this and then you need to update
your document content aka the global
variable with your current content and
then you just return again a statement
to the like the large language model
telling it that we have successfully
updated it. So I've written document has
been updated successfully. The current
content is this which is the content
which we store in the thing. Okay. So
now we define our second tool which is
the save tool. So again same decorator
we use uh like
this. And now we request the llm to give
us a file name as well. So it will it
should give us a suitable file name uh
which will be a suitable file name for
the text file and uh it will and now
this save tool will automatically handle
all the save logic. So uh as a dock
string I pass like this. So saves the
current document to a text file and
finishes the process. And the arguments
are file name which is the name for the
text file. Now, I've specifically
mentioned that we're going to be using a
text file so that the uh uh the LLM
knows that the file name which it needs
to pass has to have a txt in the end of
it. Now, if it doesn't uh by any means
to make the uh graph to make the entire
code more robust, I've also written this
if statement such that if this file name
doesn't end with a txt, just put a txt
there just uh as robust as measure. Now
again we need to uh call the global
variable again. So global document
content. Okay. Now this next bit of code
that's this is not langraph. This is
just uh whatever you put in the tool. Uh
it it doesn't have to it's not going to
be langraph related. Right. So this
piece of code is just uh some code which
allows you to save the uh contents a the
the content store in in the global
variable under the file name uh and as a
text file and I've also added this
exception uh which is a good thing for
debugging purposes where it if there's
an error it will tell me exactly what
the error is and then we can fix it.
Okay. So hopefully there won't be any
errors. Now we create a list of tools
which uh again will be update and save
because we only have two tools. And now
we actually call the uh model and how do
we call the model like
such? Now let me ask you a question. Is
this it for the model definition or do
we need something
else? Well, there's a reason I asked
that question, right? We forgotten to do
bind tools. So bind tools and tools. So
that will do. Okay. Now we actually
initialize the agent itself or the
function which will cuz remember the
agent will be a node in our graph. And
what will be the function behind that?
It will be this function which we're
about to define. So let's write this as
def r agent. And again we need to pass
in the state the agent state and it'll
return the agent state.
And okay so now this doc uh not doc
string this we need to pass in a system
message to our llm right now this llm
this system prompt will be quite large
so get ready
uh like such so in this system prompt I
have specifically said this is a system
message and the content is this you are
drafter a helpful writing assistant
you're going to help the user aka us to
update and modify documents and I've
also written some more stuff about what
the uh update or what what to do if the
user wants to update. We use the update
tool. Uh we need to use the save tool to
save it and to always show the current
document say after modifications and all
that stuff. Cool.
Okay. So, oops. There we go.
And now it's time for some robustness
measures. So when we're first
initializing the graph like when it's
the first message we're writing
obviously we're not going to straight up
say uh how would you like to change the
document right because we haven't passed
in a document yet. So if messages uh
this part if that if there's nothing in
it we will have to say something like an
introduction message right. So this is
how you can do that. So we can
say if not state messages aka if there's
nothing in the state messages then we
can say uh I'm ready to help you update
a document. What would you like to
create? and then it collects the user
input and passes it as a put stores it
as a a human message in this user
message variable. Now what if I've
already passed it uh passed in a message
or like we are on the process of
updating our draft or drafting it. Well
to do that we need this else statement
and what does this say? Well it says
what would you like to do with the
document? So this assume this says that
there's already stuff in the messages uh
state a messages key in the state how do
you want to update it further and then
we also print it uh under this emoji uh
in the terminal so the user can also see
what they've inputed and then this is
also stored in the user message. All
right. Okay.
Now we combine all of this uh all
messages aka the system prompt which was
the system message uh and we create a
list of uh list of the uh state messages
and the user message the new message
which we want the aka the update and
then we just invoke the model and how do
we invoke the model you just use the uh
model invoke okay so pretty basic code
so far there's nothing hard or nothing
uh extraordinary or something we haven't
seen before. All of this we have seen
before. And now the rest of this
function is just a print statement which
I've included. This print statement is
just for uh um making things look
prettier on the terminal. That's all it
is. You can see the true print
statements. There's the AI response
which will be printed and then there'll
be the tools uh whatever the tool
messages are that's also printed. So
that's the whole point of it. there's
nothing like to really like talk about
it here. Uh and then we also need to
obviously
return the updated state. Now remember
last time I showed you that this is also
a really convenient concise way to uh
update the states. So from now onwards
we're only going to update the states
like this. Okay. Now we create our
conditional edge function or the
function behind the conditional edge cuz
remember let me open this up. So the
conditional edge which I'm talking about
will be this this this conditional edge.
So there from tools there will be either
the select the uh the choice of going to
back to the agent or the choice of
ending it. So we need to create the
underlying function behind that. So
let's create that now
uh under this. So should continue. We've
done this many times before. it det will
determine if we should continue or end
the conversation and remember continue
or end the conversation. Okay, makes
total
sense. Okay, so
now we do this. So we get the messages
and if there's nothing in the messages,
well obviously we'll need to continue,
right? It won't go to the end part. Uh
and this is just as like a robustness
measure to be honest.
Okay. So now this piece of code
is basically saying look at the most
recent tool message or the uh recent
tool we've used and we need to check if
this tool uh has used the save tool. Now
why remember how we have two tools we
have either the uh update tool or the
save tool. If we use the update tool,
well, we will obviously need to use the
continue branch, right? But if we use
the uh save tool, well, after you saved
it, there's nothing else to do, right?
You finished your draft, you finished
everything, so might as well end the
program. That's why this end tool. So,
for the continue, uh if to go to the
continue um through the continue edge,
we have to use the update tool. And to
go to the end uh edge you need to use
the uh the save tool. So should make
sense now but don't worry if it doesn't
we will do some more print statements so
you see the workflow. Don't worry. And
lastly we need to obviously return
continue because by
default it's checked here that it's used
the save tool. The only other tool left
is the right tool and uh sorry the
update tool. And the update tool means
that we have to go to the continue edge,
right? Okay. And that's that uh function
done as well. So pretty easy still. Now
this next function is again I only coded
this just to make the print statements
in a more readable message format uh
when we printed on the terminal. So you
will see where this comes in play when
we actually start uh invoking the graph
and seeing how our process is going.
Okay, cool. Okay. So now we actually
init uh create the graph. So how do we
create the graph? We've done this many
times. We will initialize it through a
state graph. And now we will add the
nodes. So agent and tools. And the tools
will be a tool node. And again if you
notice back we had one node, two node,
the agent node and the tools node.
I'm keep I'm like reflecting back and
forth between this diagram and the code
so I can show you exactly what we're
coding. Okay. So again agent and tools
node uh we've
done now we will set the entry point at
agent which is the start point aka this
part
right and now we're going to add an edge
between agent and tools. Now we need to
obviously create this edge because the
agent needs to go to the tools right and
then this edge this directed edge and
this conditional edge creates the loop
uh which will allow for the human AI
collaboration. All right. Okay. So now
we add the conditional edge and that's
the conditional edge which I was talking
about the continue at the end aka this
condition this conditional edge from
tools. Okay.
And now the last thing we need to do is
just compile it because we've finished
the graph completely, right? There's
nothing left. We've done the start
point, we've done the end point, the
end, this conditional edges done, the
nodes done, and then this directed edge
is done and the start point is obviously
done because we've uh created a
directed. So you can see the entire
graph we have created just like that. So
again, nothing too
hard. Cool. Okay. So now we actually run
the program. And to run it, I have just
written this um function so that
everything is in a more compact way.
This is just to invoke the graph. Okay.
And let's do that. So that was the
entire code. And this code will allow
for human AI collaboration. Now, yes, we
used a global variable. And again, there
is nothing wrong with using a global
variable. I know some of you might frown
upon it, but um again, there's nothing
wrong with it. If we wanted to use more
complicated uh form uh complicated uh
stuff from langraph like the injected
state or even using something like
commands and interrupts uh we would have
to write the code slightly differently
but because this is a beginner level
course uh we've just disregarded that
completely and we found another way of
performing human AI collaboration.
Awesome. So let's actually run this now.
So let's write python draft.
py and you should be able to see all of
the things. I made my face cam slightly
smaller so you can hopefully see
everything. Perfect. So you currently
have an empty document. Could you let me
know what you like to add or create in
the document? So what would you like? So
let's say we are writing an email to our
colleague Tom saying that we can't make
it to the meeting. So let's say write me
an email. Let's say uh write me an email
to Tom saying we I cannot make it to the
meeting. Let's see what it says. So it
says
uh hi Tom I hope this message find you
well. Please let me know. Okay let's now
give it some feedback on how we how we
can improve. So and also you can also
see that it's used the update tool as
well. Perfect. So, let's say
um make sure to also have specified that
the meeting was supposed to be
at 1000 a.m. at some random negation.
Canary
Wolf.
Okay. Okay. Let's see the updated thing.
Hi, Tom. Uh you can see message meeting
at 10. Uh, can I wolf due to unforeseen
circumstances? Uh, let's I don't like
this uh your name part though. So, let's
say my name is
V and it will update that as you can
see. Perfect. Uh, what do what else do
we want to change? We can also say
something like uh let's say but tell him
that I can make it at 12 p.m. in
um New York, some random location. Okay,
I'm making this up, but you you get the
uh plan. Uh the next day. So, let's
see. And perfect. It's updated it.
However, I am available to meet at 12:00
p.m. in New York the next day.
Obviously, it's complete like rubbish
like the timings of the location I've
written. But you can see how we can just
uh use human AI collaboration here. Uh
one more thing which I don't like is
this part. I don't like the fact that
it's not a new line. So, I mean I'm
being a bit picky here. We can say
something like uh
put the II hope this message finds you
well. Awesome. And as you can see that's
done as well. So now let's say I like
it. Save it please. And what
happens? You can see that uh it used the
save tool. The tool results is document
has been updated successfully. The
current content is this and the document
has been saved to unable to attend
meeting email. Now remember we never
passed in the file name at all. That was
all generated by the by the agent
itself. And to check we need to go on
unable to attend meeting. So let's see
here it
is. And you can see it's the exact same
meeting uh exact same email we said. So,
subject, oops, best regards me. All the
exact same content. Perfect. And we
don't even need to uh make it so that
we're drafting emails. We can even drop
short stories. We can drop whatever we
want. In fact, we can also pass in uh a
previous message. So, the reason it
started off like with nothing is because
we pass in an empty list. But if you
wanted to, we could have written
something over here uh with our pre with
a already existing email or already
existing document and then it could the
model the agentic system would know that
this is what the content is the current
content how would you like to uh change
that and that is exactly how uh we will
be able to operate on our existing ones.
So you can see that this is quite a
robust thing. If we want another
example, for example, uh let's say
python drafter.
py. Okay, now watch this as well. Look
how robust this is. If I say something
like write an
email, it actually gives back questions.
So sure, what would you like the email
to say? D. So remember, it didn't even
go through any tool here. uh using
langraph we can really make the agents
quite robust and that's the thing which
I wanted to show you it doesn't always
have to pick a tool its own like LLM
like the agent itself cuz remember the
agent node has an LLM in the background
back end the bind tools function allows
it allows it scope like it increases the
scope of it uh by providing some tools
but that doesn't mean it has to use
those tools if it doesn't feel like the
need to use the tools it won't and in
this case it wanted to ask us more
questions about it. So it would say show
what would you like this email to say
because to be fair I only wrote three
words. Uh but that was what I was trying
to show you. So let's just clear this
now cuz we don't need to. And yeah you
can see perfectly works human AI
collaboration in langraph and this is
actually somewhat useful as well. Now
yes of course you can use GPT4 canvas
and all of that stuff of course but um
this is how you would do it in Lagraph.
All right. So, if you would like an
extension to this, what you could do is
add a voice feature as well. So, maybe
you could add use OpenAI whisper for uh
speech to text conversion or add 11 laps
for text to speech conversion and maybe
you can make it voice based cuz right
now I'm giving it I'm how am I
communicating it with text mode? What
about voice mode? You could also include
a GUI to this. There's a lot of stuff
which you can do on you can even have
your own knowledge base as well and
include that. So a lot of potential with
this if you want a homework for this uh
specific project that there you go. All
right. Okay. Cool. So that's the end of
this
subsection. Awesome. So now let's build
our fifth AI agent. And some of you
might have been looking forward to this.
It's retrieval augmented generation rag.
So what will the graph look like? It
will look something like this. Again,
start point, end point, really similar
to what a react agent was, right? But uh
we have two agents in this case. We have
a retriever agent and we have our main
agent LLM, right? So, and it will have
obviously a conditional edge, a loop,
and everything. Again, we're bringing
everything we've learned so far and
merging them into one. And we're also
going to be learning about a little bit
about rag. Now, I'll assume you know
what rag is. I'm not going to go too
much in detail into like the
nitty-gritty of it. But again, in the
surface level, I will obviously explain
what rag is about and everything. Okay.
So, if you're excited, let's uh let's
jump to the
code. Okay. So, now you can see that
I've already done all of the imports
which we'll need. But you'll notice how
there are these four imports which we
haven't come across yet. Now, rather
than explain them from the get- go, I
will explain them as they come because
it'll make more sense. uh it'll make
more intuitive sense that way. Okay. So
now I'm going to be loading our uh ENV
file which contains all the API keys.
And this time I'm going to be
initializing our LLM differently. Well,
slightly differently. It's the same LLM,
but why did I say differently? Because
I've passed in a new parameter called
temperature. Now for those of you who do
not know what temperature is, it's
essentially a parameter which depicts
how stochastic the model outputs how
stoastic you want the model outputs to
be. So because I've set it to be zero,
temperature equal to zero makes the
model output more deterministic.
Similarly, if I had set the temperature
to be one, the model output would have
been more stochastic. Okay. So now we
create the embedding
model. And the embedding model uh is
what's going to convert our text into
vector embeddings. Right? Uh so this
will be the layout for it. Now please
note one important thing which is the
embedding model has to be compatible
with the LLM we're using. You can use
whatever LLM you want but make sure the
embedding model uh is compatible with
it. For example uh let's say we're using
GBD40 uh an open model but the embedding
model we're using is from Olama some
random model. Now that they wouldn't
most likely they're not going to be
compatible. Why? Because there's so many
differences between them. One potential
difference could be the vector
dimension. So just a rule of thumb. Make
sure the LLM and the embedding model is
compatible. Okay. Awesome. So now we're
going to specify the PDF part. So this
is the stock market performance 2024
PDF. And essentially this is just a
document which I created which contains
um a lot about the stock market
performance. Okay. Uh I can show you
that right now actually. So this
contains nine pages and is just a
document containing about some stock
market details in 2024. Okay. Awesome.
So now um in case you've specified the
uh you have put the PDF in a wrong
directory or if it can't find it uh this
error will pop up. So again I've just
put this for debugging purposes if you
use the code which I provided on GitHub.
Okay. Now this will load the PDF and you
can see pi PDF loader is one of the
imports which we made here. So again
it's in the name and the common. It just
simply loads the PDF. Okay. Uh and this
try and accept command uh just checks if
the PDF is there. And pages is equal to
PDF loader.load. So this essentially
says how many pages are there in the
document. So you can see there's nine
pages in our document. So if I run this
command, if I run this, so clear
python rag agent.py
py it should say nine
pages.
So there we go. PDF has been loaded and
has nine pages as expected. Right? Okay.
Now it's time for the chunking process.
Now what is chunking? First look at
this. There are two parameters which
I've specified. Chunk size which is
a,000 and chunk overlap which is 200. So
let's break this down a bit. Going back
to our document. So chunk size was 1,000
tokens. So let's say that this was a
chunk for example. Okay, obviously
that's not going to be a thousand
tokens, but just as like uh
demonstration purposes, let's assume it
is. So this is saying as soon as you've
reached 1,000 tokens, you create a new
chunk. So let's say 1,000 tokens ended
here. So this would be the start of a
new chunk like such. Okay. And you keep
going and going and going until the end
of the document. But what if the what
about the second parameter? The second
parameter is specified overlap and
that's essentially saying let me use it
in a different color that your chunks
consecutive chunks should have some
tokens um which are which exist in both
for example because it was 200 the
second chunk is not going to start from
here. It's actually going to start
something like
this. They're obviously going to be the
same length uh in terms of tokens but
they will have some tokens which will be
in both chunks. So for example, this
part will be in both cuz that's the
overlap. 200 tokens to be precise. Okay,
so that was just a brief overview of
what chunks are in uh rag. Okay, so
that's that part done. And again, this
recursive character text splitter is one
of the imports we did. Okay,
so this text splitter um chunking
process, we now apply it to all of the
pages, all of our nine pages in our
document. Okay.
And this piece of code essentially
saying this, the chroma vector database,
we're going to be using a chroma vector
database to store all of our vector
embeddings, by the way. But the uh the
place where we want our chroma vector
database to be will be specified in this
file path. And the collection's name
will be called stock market. Now, you
can specify it wherever you want
obviously, but I've just specified it to
be in the same
folder. Okay.
So this is just an if statement to make
sure that uh if this is the first time
we're running this command uh if we're
running this file uh if this collection
doesn't exist we will create the um
collection in the specified directory.
Okay, again not too hard yet. Now here
comes a try except command u try accept
block. So this is where we actually
create the vector embedding uh where we
create the chroma vector um
database and these are just parameters
which I specify. So for example, how I
want the pages to be split, what
embeddings to use, where to store it and
the collection name. The collection name
being stock market, right? And if there
is an error, it will throw an error and
if it's successful, it'll print on the
terminal. Okay, awesome. So now we
create something called a retriever. So
the retriever is quite important in rag.
It's well obviously the first part of
rag retrieval augmented generation. So
the retriever is what actually well
retrieves the chunks the most similar
chunks. Um the search type which we're
going to use similarity. It's just the
default anyway. Uh you don't really need
to know how that works to be honest. But
what you do need to know is this part.
So in this code I have made sure that
every time uh it goes the amount of
chunks it uh outputs back is five. Why?
Because k here is the amount of chunks
to be returned. So I've set it as five.
Now I'm pretty sure if we go to the
actual documents here the default the
default is four. Okay. So uh this is
just a parameter which you can uh set.
Now you don't want it to be too high of
course or too low. So you want like a
good middle ground and 405 is a good
middle ground in my opinion. Okay. So
now let's create our tool. So again we
use decorator tool. And the tool's name
is going to be this retriever tool. It
will input it will take in a query and
it'll output a string. So the dock
string is as follows. This tool searches
and returns the information from our
document. Okay self-explanatory.
uh and obviously we need to invoke it to
the retriever. So whatever query we ask
for example uh what was Apple's
performance in 2024 that will be the
query and that will be passed to our
retriever which will grab all the chunks
the most the top five most similar
chunks. Okay. Now if we don't if there's
nothing similar uh which it finds for
example if I say something like uh who's
Bob the builder something like that
right obviously Bob the builder is not
in this document uh so it will return as
I found no relevance information in the
document and uh this will be passed to
our LLM agent okay if it does find it
though what we'll do is we'll create an
empty list and we will store all of the
similarity
um us the all of the chunks which it
found and then return those results uh
through this. Okay, still it's quite
easy still uh and this piece of code
we've already come across. There is only
one tool. So we just bind that tool to
our
LLM. And this also code we have also
we've uh done many times. It's the uh
creation of the agent state. And again
we're using our add messages reducer
function. All of this we've covered many
times so you should be quite familiar
with it. Okay. So now we create the
should continue function and the should
continue function uh is going to be the
underlying function between our
conditional edge behind our conditional
edge. So it will check if the last
message contains any tool calls. If it
does then we um proceed. If it doesn't
then we'll just end
right. Okay. So now we specify the
system prompt. Now this system prompt is
going to be quite big. So let me copy
and paste it here. Now the reason is
quite big is I want to specify as much
information to the LLM so that it knows
what to do. Right? So I've just said
you're an intelligent AI assistant who
answers questions about the document uh
loaded into your knowledge base. Uh you
can read the rest if you would like. But
I've also written this. Please always
site the specific parts of the document
you use in your answers. This is really
just to make sure it's not
hallucinating. Right? because as we know
hallucination is quite a big problem
with LLMs. So this is just to make sure
um hallucinations are kept to a bare
minimum. Okay. All right. So now we
create a dictionary of our tools and we
now create the underlying function which
will be our LLM agent. So this function
will call the LLM with the current state
and you can see it converts the messages
to a list passes the system messages and
passes it to our LLM which is defined
like this and it will just return the
messages aka the updated
state. Okay, this should be like such.
Okay, awesome. So now we create our
second agent which will be the retriever
agent which you saw on the in the graph
which I showed you in the introduction.
So the retriever agent executes the tool
calls from the LLM response. So what is
this code actually saying? Well, all in
all, this massive piece of code really
just says if there is a tool, if the
tool name is within the is a proper
specified tool, aka if it's retriever
tool, then actually run it. If it's not,
then we will output the result as input
in incorrect tool name. Please retry and
select the tool from list of available
tools. It's just for checking if a if
the tool which is decided from the LLM
is valid or not. So that's all what this
is doing. If it is valid, it will invoke
it and we will store the results uh like
this and we will return that. Okay.
Again this should be agent state like
such. Okay. So we've created all of our
our two um AI agents now and now we're
going to create the graph itself. So
like how we've done initialize it
through state graph and then we're going
to add our two AI agents as nodes with
their respective
actions and we are now going to add the
conditional edge. So which will be llm
which will be start from l lm and the
should continue function is the function
which will be um the underlying function
and this is a uh true false statement
and this is the edge the set entry point
all of this we've covered many times so
again should be quite familiar to you
and last but not least compile the graph
and store it in a ragation okay one last
thing though uh I've created
this function and this function is just
a function which allows us to keep
asking questions to our graph and keep
receiving qu uh answers back and if you
want to exit we can write either exit or
quit um and it's just a simple while
loop that's all it is okay and it prints
the
answer okay so that's the actual code
complete now we're going to test it and
see uh if the if this is reliable or
not. Okay. Okay. So, let's actually test
this now um by doing python rag agent.
py. Let's run this.
Okay. PDF has been loaded and has nine
pages. Created chromo vector data uh
chroma database vector store. So, where
is this stored? Well, you can see that
this is uh by the way, this will all be
on GitHub as well. But this is the
Chroma database and its respective um
bin bin files. Okay. And we can even
view it.
But it'll look something like that.
Okay. But because this has been created,
this is a good sign that everything is
working. Okay. So, let's ask a simple
question. Uh let's ask something
like how was the S&P 500
uh performing in 2024? Enter. So it's
calling the retriever tool uh with the
query this uh its result then puts that
complete back to the model and the model
has given us this. In 2024, the S&P 500
delivered a total return of this with a
23% increase late 1990s and all of that
stuff uh magnificent 7 and has given us
the uh respective uh citations as well.
Now, how can we verify this is uh
correct? Let's
see. So, notice
how if you remember this part, the total
return of approximately 25%.
Well, the reason I prom I asked it for
this is because that's exactly what uh
over here it stated the benchmark
roughly at 25% 23%. Uh remember this
late 1990s part that's exactly what this
is saying here as well and this was
correctly defined in the first document.
So this is clearly working now right it
can't have made up this information. So
that means our rag is successfully set
up. Now I can ask as many questions I
possib as I want now but now let's see
if there is something which is not
included in the rag. So for example we
can say something like how did open AI
perform in
2024 retrieve a tool called back to the
model. Okay, now look at this. Uh if I
do it like that, the documents do not
provide specific information about
OpenAI stock performance, which is true
cuz OpenAI is not a publicly traded
company. Uh and yeah, it got that
correct. So no hallucination there. So
you can clearly see that this is working
uh completely fine. And that ladies and
gentlemen is how you create a retrieval
augmented generation graph in Langraph.
Okay.
Awesome. All right people. So that
brings us to the end of this course and
I hope you liked it and I hope you
learned a lot about
Langraph. Now although this course is
finishing here, your journey in Langraph
is just beginning. Just think about how
many cool AI projects, AI agent systems
you can make now. Maybe your own Javis
as well. Now, if you have any further
questions related to the course material
or just things in general or just want
to say hi, you can always message me on
LinkedIn. With that being said, thank
you so much for watching this course and
I hope to see you in another course.
Take care.